片名：钢铁擂台/铁甲钢拳
翻译：闲闲的猛男 校对：目前没有
翻译的很辛苦 句句推敲 认为好的按声赞 但是转载 请考虑原创的辛苦 不要把原讯息删掉！
等一下 等一下 来了
Hang on, hang on. Come on.
Charlie你在哪里？更重要的是 几时还钱？
Where are you, Charlie? More importantly, where is my money?
- 你还欠我三万元 - Jack 我马上可以还你
- You're into me for 30 grand. - Jack, I'm going to pay you.
我不是Jack 我是比尔
This ain't Jack! It's Bill Panner.
你还欠Jack钱？你最好先还我
You owe Jack money, too? You pay me first!
比尔 兄弟 钱我准备好了 就在我手上
Bill. We're good, buddy. I got your money. It's right here in my hand.
那我们约个地………
Why don't we meet up on the?
- 喂？你的讯号很差 - 我听不到你
- Your phone's going all screwy. Hello? - I'm losing you.
我听不清楚你说什么...
I can't hear what you're say...
先生您好 那个是突击者号吗？
Hey, mister. Is that Ambush?
- 是的 - 我们可以看看吗？
- Yeah. - Can we see him?
- 你们想看？- 耶
- You want to see him? - Yeah.
等一下！
Give me a minute.
这个是...
This...
...突击者号！ 启动 启动！
is Ambush. Wakey, wakey.
- 他要跟谁比赛？- 其实他是要跟...
- What robot is he fighting? - Actually he's going to fight...
噢 小妹妹 你要干嘛？
Whoa, little lady. What are you doing?
我可不可以跟他照个像？
Can we get a picture with him?
当然可以 五块钱
Sure. For five dollars.
照个像要五元？你开玩笑吧？
You want five dollars? Seriously?
没开玩笑 马上给我五元
No, I want five dollars immediately.
走吧！小朋友！
Come on, guys.
- 好啦！我开玩笑的 三元就好 - 你慢慢想吧
- All right, I'm kidding. Three bucks. - Whatever.
- 那就二块半好了？- 你这个逊咔！
- How about $2.50? - You suck!
又是一个乡巴佬小镇 是吧？
It's going to be one of those towns, huh?
各位先生女士们 欢迎来到2020年圣兰卓乡村市集
Welcome, ladies and gentlemen, to the 2020 San Leandro County Fair.
各位请坐 我们将要开始了
Please take your seats. We're almost ready to get this thing started.
讲好的是我的机器人对抗800磅的牛
I was told my bot was fighting an 800-pound steer.
那只牛绝对不止800磅 你这个呆头
That is not 800 pounds, knucklehead.
Charlie"无所不能小子" 肯顿 看来你也老了 老朋友
Charlie "the Can Do Kid" Kenton. Time has not been good to you, my friend.
- 里奇 麻烦大了 - 不要激动 老朋友
- Ricky, we got a big problem here. - Slow down there, hoss.
最后一次我们的见面是在桑休士顿中心
Last time I saw you, you were staring at the ceiling at the Sam Houston Center
我正好赏你一记右叉拳
with the taste of my right cross all over your face.
- 准备好了吗？- 耶
- Are we good to go here? - Yeah.
说好的是我的机器人对抗800磅的牛 代价是三千元
We agreed that my boxer would fight an 800-pound steer for three grand.
- 真的嘛？- 是的 说好的是这样
- Am I right? - Yes, sir. We did.
但是那只牛看起来大概是2000磅
That bull is like 2,000 pounds.
打个商量
I'll tell you something.
如果你的机器人不打 你一分钱都拿不到 怎么样？
Your bot don't fight, you don't get paid! How about that?
滚吧你！
Get the hell out of here.
要不要赌大一点 我的机器人跟你的牛对打
Why don't we make this more interesting. My bot against your bull, straight up.
- 赌多少？- 二万 胜方独赢
- How much? - Twenty grand, winner takes all.
- 二万？你有钱可以赌？- 藏在我车上
- Twenty grand. You got 20 grand? - In a safe in my truck.
Charlie 好吧！
All right, Charlie.
二万就二万 但是如果你输了绕跑
Twenty grand it is, but if you lose and you welch,
我见你一次就海扁你一次
I'll come after you and beat you to within an inch of your life.
你知道我没骗你 因为我时常在扁你
You know that I can do that because I already done done it!
别靠我那么那么近 你这个拳击场上的娘娘腔 到底比不比？
In life you get too close, in the ring you stand back like a girl. Just shake.
那好 握手然后“嘣” 像以前一样 你要不要再被我扁？
All right. Shake and pow! Just like that once again. You want to dance again?
帮这家伙加加油 给他点好运 他需要点运气 耶！
Cheer for this guy. Give him some luck. He needs some luck, y'all.
不要再惹那只牛！
Don't touch that bull.
各位先生女士们 我来问一下；
Ladies and gentlemen, I got to ask,
这里有没有人是机器人拳击赛的粉丝？
do we have any fans of robot boxing here today?
各位好朋友 注意听着 我了解………
Now, listen, friends, I understand
不是每个人都可以付得起300元的门票
we can't all afford to go all the way over there to Dallas
然后一路到达拉斯去看世界杯机器人拳击大赛！
and pay $300 for one of those World Robot Boxing League fights.
所以我决定给你们带来一场机器人拳击比赛
So, I decided that I would bring a robot boxing match
就在这里 我们的圣卓兰乡村市集上
right here to our little fair here in San Leandro.
喜欢吗？
How about that?
各位先生女士们 我来介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, I introduce to you,
突击者号！
Ambush!
来吧 开始吧！
Let's do it!
好样的 大家伙
All right, big fella.
他是不是一个大家伙啊？
He's a big fella, ain't he?
转一圈 让大家看看你有多威猛！
Take a turn. Let them see how beautiful you are.
看看你有多有力！
Show them some power.
大家赶快看 他在为我们表演功夫喔
Look at that. He's getting all kung fu-y on us.
耶 大家伙！
Yeah, big fella.
突击者号的对手是年度公牛大赛……
Ambush's opponent today, he's last year's runner-up
击倒率最高的………
in the baddest of the bulls competition,
各位先生女士们
ladies and gentlemen,
黑色闪电！
Black Thunder!
- 开始吧 - 战斗开始咯
- Let's get it on! - Let's get this thing started.
你就这么点能耐？
Is that all you got?
耶！兄弟 干劲拿出来！
Yeah, brother. Bring it on.
干掉他 干掉他！
Take him, take him.
突击者一掌把这只愤怒的牛翻倒在地
Ambush lays the smackdown on that prime beef.
我还有很多绝招 大家伙 我们才刚暖身
I got more for you, big fella. We're just getting started.
准备 现在 跳
OK. Jump, now!
突击者一掴掀翻黑色闪电
Ambush, decks Black Thunder,
但是当你惹毛一只公牛 你就最好小心他们的牛角
but when you mess with the bull, you're going to get the horns.
噢 你喜欢是吧！我看得出来 喜欢这个
You like that. I can tell. You like that.
转身小心
Turn around!
里奇！里奇！够了我们认输！
Ricky! Ricky, stop this thing!
来吧！我们还要战斗 跳 跳一下 ！
Come on. We're still in this thing. Just hop. Hop.
就是这样 来吧！
That's it. Come on.
里奇 够了！ 我们认输！
Ricky, enough! Enough!
你的机器人被痛扁的声音盖过了你的声音
I can't hear you over the sound of your robot being destroyed.
杀了他！杀了他！杀了他！
Kill! Kill! Kill!
快点 站起来！
Come on, get up.
站起来！快点！
Get up! Come on!
不要！
No!
不要！不要！不要！
Come on, no. No, no, no!
各位先生女士们 让我们为我们的勇士喝彩吧！
Ladies and gentlemen, let's hear it for our warriors out here today
就在今天 就在我们的圣兰卓乡村市集
at the 2020 San Leandro County Fair.
感谢你们的参观
Thank you for coming out,
我保证下次会更精彩的
and we'll see you next time, because there will be one.
把脚还给我
Give me that leg.
可以 要五块钱
Sure. For five dollars.
活该 ！
Boo-yah!
各位先生女士们 很好 不可思议的好玩对吧？
All right! That was ridiculous fun, now wasn't it, ladies and gentlemen?
Charlie男孩 等下我来拿钱 你最好准备好！
I'm going to come by for my money, Charlie boy. You best have it.
- 大家一起喊 "嗨！" - 嗨！
- Everybody say "hey!" - Hey!
- 大家一起喊 "喝！" - 喝！
- Everybody say "ho!" - Ho!
拽不起来了吧？哈哈！小机器人！
How about that? How you doing there, little robot?
我的钥匙 他妈的！
My keys, damn it.
再靠近一步 我就狠狠的扁你一顿
One more step and I'll drop you like your girlfriend.
Charlie 不要紧张
Charlie, relax.
我不会付钱 那是不公平的比赛 甚至花了我最后一个机器人！
I'm not paying you. That was a bogus fight. It cost me my last robot.
- 让我们先说 - 你还记得卡洛琳法罗吗？
- Just listen to us. - Do you recall Caroline Fallon?
她是我的前女友 我已经十年没见过她了 她想干嘛？
She's my ex-girlfriend. I haven't seen her in ten years. What does she want?
她死了
Nothing. She died.
你还记不记得Max
Do you recall Max Kenton?
他是我儿子 他应该已经九岁了
He's my son. He's got to be nine.
- 十一岁 - 十一岁 好吧！
- Eleven. - Eleven. OK.
他也死了？
Is he dead, too?
不 他还好好的 所以我们才来
No, he's fine. That's why we're here.
翻译：闲闲的猛男 校对：目前没有
今天法庭要判决Max 十一岁
This court is convened to address the custodial status
他的监护权的所属
of one Max Kenton, age 11.
母亲是刚过世的卡洛琳法罗 父亲是Charlie肯顿
Mother, Caroline Fallon, deceased. Father, Charles Kenton.
黛博拉 法罗 巴恩 你是小男孩的阿姨吗？
Debra Fallon Barnes, you're the boy's aunt.
是的 就像我所表达的 我的先生 马文 他很健康
Yes. As I've already told you, my husband, Marvin, is wealthy,
我们可以好好的照顾Max
and we can more than provide for Max.
我认为这样很好 但是根据德州的法律
I appreciate that, but per Texas state law, without a written will
如果他没出席的生父Charlie肯顿
next of kin retains custody.
没有放弃他的抚养权的话
Charles Kenton, who is aware of this custody hearing,
我们还在等他出席
and we are expecting him...
我要一个新的机器人
I need a new robot now.
我帮突击者在下周六安排一场大比赛
I had a big fight for Ambush next Saturday.
我现在要赶去处理一件事
I got to show up with something.
大声公要卖吗？大声公是杀手级的！
Noisy Boy is for sale? In his day, Noisy Boy was a killer.
多少钱？很划算 有没有其他的毛病？
How much? That's a good deal. What's wrong with him?
我要买
I can live with that.
但是我现在没有钱
I don't have it.
Charlie肯顿在Max一出生的时候就没有尽到父亲的义务
Charles Kenton waived all of his rights to custody right after the boy was born.
我们可以更好地照顾Max
I can more than provide for Max.
你是Charlie肯顿吗？
Please be Charles Kenton.
是的 就是Charlie
Charlie, yeah.
我来签一些文件 放弃一些权力
I'm here to sign some paper that releases my rights
放弃我小孩的监护权
to the custody of my son.
所以我才来 我是应该来吧？
That's why I'm here. Do I need to be here?
Charlie
Charlie.
你还记得我吗？
Do you even remember me?
- 黛博拉 卡洛琳的妹妹 - 是哦 黛博拉 你还好吗？
- Debra, Caroline's sister. - Yeah, Debra. How are you?
肯顿先生 请坐！
Mr. Kenton. Please take a seat.
法官大人 我可以先去看看我的外甥吗？
Your Honor, may I please go and see my nephew now?
可以！请去吧！
Yes, you may.
- 你呢？肯顿先生！ - 什么？
- How about you, Mr. Kenton? - What?
如果你想要 你可以跟你儿子独处一会儿！
You can spend some time with him, if you'd like.
- 跟我儿子？- 是的 你儿子！
- With the kid? - Yeah, the kid.
- Max 你儿子！ - 好的！
- Max. Your son? - All right.
你跟机器人在一起太久了 现在也像机器一样没有感情
You've been working with those robots for so long, you've become one.
宝贝 你在这里等一下 我马上回来
Honey, you wait right here. I'm going to be back.
甜心 不急 慢慢来！
You take all the time you need, sweetheart.
法官大人 如果可以的话 这么重要的事
Your Honor, I'd like to, at this juncture,
我想出去一下跟我的律师商量一下！
step out and call my attorney, if that's all right.
当然可以！
Please.
来吧！你怎么还不来？
Come on. Come on. There you are.
他会被领养的
He'll be in a foster home.
他们会找到一个年轻有活力的家庭的 是的！
No, they find good families. Young. Energetic. Yeah.
感谢你 麦克 我会的 好的
Thanks, Michael. I will. OK.
- 马文巴恩 我是黛博拉的先生 - 是哦 耶！
- Marvin Barnes. I'm Debra's husband. - Right, yeah.
黛博拉是真的很想领养Max
Debra really wants to adopt Max.
- 我是很想完成他的愿望 - 七万五千元
- I'm up for it. But... - Seventy-five grand.
七万五千元？你是说真的？
$75,000? You're serious?
还有一件事是...
The thing is...
...我们这个夏天要去意大利度假
we're supposed to go to Italy this summer
跟我最好的朋友及他太太
with my oldest friend and his wife.
二个月都在图斯卡尼
Two months in Tuscany and all over.
只有你们四个 听起来不错！
Just the four of you. Sounds nice.
我们八月底才会回来纽约
We'll be back in New York by the end of August.
到八月 那就十万
In August. A hundred.
- 十万？- 没错
- $100,000? - You heard me.
- 你疯了吗？- 没有比你太太还疯
- You're crazy. - Not nearly as crazy as your wife
如果我把儿子的抚养权签给了德州政府
if you tell her I just signed over that kid to the state of Texas.
那么你太太就得不到他想要的
There's a real way everyone gets what they want here.
所以我建议你这样做
So here's what you're going to do.
你告诉你的太太我只会把抚养权给他
You're going to tell your wife I'll only sign over custody to her
如果我能跟我儿子共度一个暑假
if I get to spend the summer with the kid first.
就说我真的很愧疚
Just tell her how guilty she made me feel
我一直没有尽到父亲的责任
for being such a terrible absentee dad,
我多想补偿小孩一些父亲的天伦之乐
how I want to make good with junior, a little fatherly bonding, whatnot.
她会买账的 然后大家都得到自己想要的
She'll buy it, you get to be the hero and everybody wins.
好吧 但是不准告诉黛伯拉有关钱的事
OK. But not a word about the money to Debra, you understand?
我了解
I understand.
今晚我们载Max过去的时候 我会先付你五万块
I'll give you 50 grand tonight when we drop off Max
然后等我们八月回来 再付你五万
and the other 50 when we get back in August
而且你要带他到纽约给我们
and you deliver him to us in New York.
很高兴跟你做生意
Pleasure doing business with you.
法官大人 很高兴我们都仔细的考虑
Your Honor, I'm happy we all took the time
作出对每个人都好的决定
to make the best decision for everyone.
- 高兴吗？- 是的 是我
- Happy? - Yeah, it's me.
我要买下大声公 我有钱了
I'm buying Noisy Boy. I got the money.
把它带到泰利健身房 我等一下就到
Take him to Tallet's Gym and I'll meet you there.
哈？
Hello?
百丽？
Bailey?
有人在这里等你付钱
Some guy is here with the robot you're buying,
千万不要放我鸽子
and it smells like disaster to me.
我也很高兴见到你
Nice to see you, too.
- 你知道你很可爱吗？- 少来一套
- Might I also say how cute you look. - Give it up.
天啊 我要冲个凉 你也要吗？一起来吧！
God, I need a shower. You want to take a shower? Come on.
我要说清楚一件事
Let me make something clear.
有个可怕的人带着个机器人
A creepy dude with a robot in a box
坐在健身房门口等我二个小时了
has been sitting outside my gym for two hours.
如果暂时先不考虑这件在我家门口的黑市交易
Putting aside the fact that you're doing
你怎么付这个钱？
what I'm guessing is a black market deal on my doorstep,
你不是刚毁了突击者号？
how will you pay him when Ambush just got destroyed?
钱快到了 安抚他一下！
The money is on its way. Just distract him.
我一直在安抚他 我快累死了！
I have been. It's exhausting.
- 你最好了 - 耶？是吗？
- You're the best. - Yeah? Really?
那就是你刚买了四万五千元的机器人但是你还欠我六千的房租？
Is that why you're buying a $45,000 robot when you owe me six grand in rent?
- 因为我最好说话？- 三千
- Because I'm the best? - Three.
六千 而且告诉你 已经有人要买下我的地方了
Six. There is a guy with real money who wants to buy this place.
少来了 你不会真的想卖掉你老爸留给你的健身房？
Come on. Like you're really going to sell your dad's gym.
如果你不付房租 我也付不出钱 那我就逼不得已了
If you don't make rent, I can't make payments and I won't have a choice.
你父亲会从坟墓里面爬起来踢你的
Your father would climb out of his grave and kick your ass
- 如果你卖了这个地方 - 我父亲会爬出他的坟墓
- if you sold this place. - My father would climb out of his grave
踢你的屁股
and kick your ass.
百丽？
Bailey?
- 不要 - 不要做什么？
- Don't. - Don't what?
不要那么做
Don't do that.
- 不要做什么？- 不要做那种小狗表情
- Don't what? - Don't do that thing.
- 不对 你喜欢拳击 - 不对
- No, you like that thing. - No.
- 是的 - 不对 我不喜欢拳击
- Yeah. - No, I don't like that thing.
我习惯了 简单地说 但是我现在喜欢钱
I used to. Once. Briefly. Now I like money more.
- 我不相信你 - 我不管
- I don't believe you. - I don't care.
马文
Marvin.
钱到了
Your money has arrived.
马文
Marv.
五万 说好的
Fifty grand, as promised.
这个是我们的号码及我们在欧洲的联络方式
Here are all our numbers and contact info over in Europe.
嗯 所以都安排好了
So that's everything there.
马文告诉我你想跟马克思小聚一段时间
So Marvin tells me you want this time with Max.
- 是的 - 你做的很对
- Yeah. - You did the right thing,
把监护权给我
giving me custody.
卡洛琳也会希望你这么做
Caroline would have wanted that.
现在 请八月27号准时带Max到纽约给我们
Now, have him back in New York on August 27th.
没问题
That's a deal.
好的 我们去接Max 好的 ？我们去接Max
OK, let's go get Max. OK? Let's get Max.
还好吗？你要到另外一边 我来带Max？
It's OK. You want to go around the other side here and I'll get Max?
嗨 Max 再见 小老弟
Hey. Max. See you, pal.
亲爱的Max 我们暑假过后见
Max, we'll see you at the end of the summer, honey.
我是Charlie
I'm Charlie.
好久不见了 我是...
It's been a long time. You know, I'm your...
- 你搞死我了 - 嘴巴真干净
- You screwed me. - Nice mouth.
你知道他们现在要去哪里？
Do you know where they're going?
- 意大利？- 是啊 意大利
- Italy? - Yeah, Italy.
那我为什么要跟你呆在这个鸟地方？
So how did I get stuck here with you?
不要激动 你还有后面一辈子的时间跟他们在一起
Relax, kid. You got a whole life of fine living ahead of you.
Charlie
Charlie!
那个老兄气疯了 他要走了！
Dude's pissed. He's going to take off.
- 马文给你钱了吗？- 来 刚刚给了
- Did Marvin give you that money? - Here, just close the deal.
我等下过去 好吗？
I'll be right there, OK?
- 我是百丽 - Max
- I'm Bailey. - Max.
Max 肯顿
Max Kenton.
- 这是你的... - 是的我儿子
- So this is your... - Yeah, it's him.
不要担心好吗？
Don't worry about it, OK?
我要照顾你们二个跟...
I'm looking at you two and...
请把大声公放在店里好吗？谢谢你！
Just go and put Noisy in the shop, please? Thank you.
我出去的时候 你跟百丽呆在店里好吗？
You're going to stay here with her while I'm on the road.
- 他给你多少钱？- 你误会了
- How much did he give you? - You're coming at this the wrong way.
不 告诉我 我要知道
No, tell me. I want to know.
好吧！五万元
Fifty thousand, OK?
他给我五万元来让我放弃你
He gave me $50,000 to sign you over to her.
你可以住嘴吗？
Will you shut up now?
你把我卖了？
You sold me?
没有那么糟！
Sounds worse than it is.
- 真的？- 那是对你最好的
- Really. - It's to take care of you.
那我要分账分一半
Give me half the money and you won't have to.
- 你要去哪里？- 把钱给我 我自己会照顾自己
- Where are you going to go? - Give me the money. I'll be fine.
我答应你阿姨 暑假结束的时候会送你去纽约的
I told your aunt I'll get you to New York at the end of the summer.
现在你只在乎黛博拉阿姨？
Now you're concerned for Aunt Debra?
你用五万把我卖掉 你欠我二万五
You sold me for 50 grand. You owe me half!
我没有钱 我把钱花在机器人身上 花完了 没钱了！
I don't have it! I spent the money on a robot. It's gone! OK? Gone!
我完蛋了
I'm through here.
你买了什么？
What do we got?
大声公到了
Noisy Boy has arrived.
贴满了海关及航空公司的标签
That's a lot of airline stickers and customs tags.
- 他到过世界的每个角落 - 伦敦 日本 巴西 巴尔的摩...
- He's been all over the world. - London, Japan, Brazil, So Paulo...
这二年还没有到过北美
Hasn't seen North American soil in over two years.
或许是因为这样 价格才那么便宜 天才！
Maybe that's why you got such a good price, genius.
决定留下来了？
Decided to stay?
百丽会照顾你几个礼拜
This is Bailey. She'll be looking after you for a few weeks.
这几周请帮我照顾小孩
I need you to look after the kid for a few weeks.
- 我要一半的钱 - 你还要讨论这个？
- I want half that money. - Are we back to this again?
那个是真正的搏击机器人？
Is there a real robot boxer in there?
大声公 你有没有听过它？
Noisy Boy's in there. You ever heard of him?
当然 它在2016年跟罗比肯争夺世界冠军
Of course. He fought Rubicon for the WRB belt in 2016.
老天爷 他看起来太好了！
Holy crap, he looks amazing.
它的盔甲已经换过了 我们看看里面的零件是不是一样好
His composite armor has been replaced. Let's see if the insides look as good.
我已经反复看过他跟罗比肯的比赛快20次了
I've watched that fight with Rubicon like 20 times.
它实在应该在第三回合击败他的
He should have had him in the third round,
但是罗比肯打出一记幸运的右拳 结束了！
but Rubicon got lucky with a huge right and ended it.
不要激动 他现在是我们的了
Relax, kid, he's on our side.
- 不好玩 - 有点好玩
- Not funny. - Kind of funny.
你知道他有声控装置吧？
You know he has voice recognition, right?
- 不 没有吧？- 他不是普通级别的
- No, he doesn't. - He didn't in the League.
当大声公在巴西的时候 他们应该装上的
When Noisy fought in Brazil, they must have put it in.
巴西人就是喜欢对机器人说话的那种怪咔
Brazilians are crazy about that talk-to-your-robot crap.
右 左 上击拳！
Right, left, uppercut!
坏掉了！ 右 左 上击拳！
Doesn't work. Right, left, uppercut!
我就知道便宜没好货的
I knew that price was too good to be true. We got screwed.
- 让我看看 我来修修看 - 看看它有多好吧！
- Let me see if I can fix it. - Look how good he looks, too.
二秒就好 我看看！
Give me two seconds. Let me look at something!
- 你为什么不验验货？- 不要紧张
- Why didn't you ask to look at it? - Relax!
你是不是用日文？
Was that Japanese?
我看看可不可以切换到英文！
Let me see if I can reset him to English.
你怎么会讲日文？
How do you know Japanese?
电视游戏
Video games.
你会玩日文游戏？
You play video games in Japanese?
走私来的日本游戏都比较好的
Japanese bootlegs are always better.
给我吧
Give me that.
已经改到英文模式 而且我找到他的命令集了
He's reset to English, and I found his command matrix.
制造商已经预设了很多的组合拳了
They have pre-loaded a bunch of combinations.
他们应该要附个说明书的
They should be listed here.
上下击拳组合
Top salvo!
我早告诉你了
What did I tell you?
重拳下击组合
Gravity One Downtown!
我真是太幸运了
I was due for some good luck!
- 不客气 - 谢谢你
- You're welcome. - Thank you.
百丽 帮我装上车 我要去赚的钱了
Bailey, help me put him in the truck. I am going to go and get your money.
- 把钥匙给我 - 我要跟你一起去
- Give me the keys. - I'm coming with you.
- 你不能去 - 为什么？
- No, you're not. - Why not?
因为我不想让你去 好吗？
Because I don't want you with me, OK?
让我一起去 不然你就只能到下水沟钓你的钥匙了
I'm either coming with you, or you're fishing for your keys in the sewer.
老人家 你决定咯！
Your choice. What's it going to be, old man?
噢 老天爷 好险 快掉下去了噢
Oh, my God. That was close, wasn't it?
- 不要再那样做 - 吓到你了是吧？
- Don't do that again. - That's scaring you, isn't it?
不要再那样做是吗？
Don't do this again?
上车 马上上车！把钥匙给我先！
Get in. Just get in. Give me the keys first.
等我先上车再给你 大老爹！
Wait till I get in the truck. Thanks, Big Pops.
快乐的行程
Sweet ride.
系上安全带 闭嘴！
Put on your seatbelt and don't talk.
我要谈一下赌金
I'm taking all bets!
跟上 不要落后
Keep up. Stay close.
Charlie肯顿来了
Charlie Kenton is in the house!
- 很好 很好 - 进来 老兄！
- All right, all right. - Come on, man!
- 这个是大声公吗？- 是的 唯一的
- Is that Noisy Boy? - The one and only.
大声公来了！
That's Noisy Boy!
大声公是日本过来的 他们那里的拳击有点软
Noisy's been in Japan. Softer bots over there.
- 你确定今晚要打？- 你有哪些人？
- Sure you want to fight him tonight? - What do you got?
你知道的 他可以打败这里的每一个机器人
He can take any bot in this place. You know it.
你可以随意挑选你的对手
You can have any undercard you want.
五千的保证金
Five thousand guaranteed.
每一回合一千 如果你的机器人撑得过去
A thousand every round your bot survives.
直到倒下
Fight till the death!
不 给我最重要的压轴
No. Give me the main event.
- 少来 - 这是大声公哩
- Come on. - This is Noisy Boy.
这是松本原厂的机器人
An original Tak Mashido bot.
大声公是世界级别的 拜托
He was a World Robot League boxer. Come on!
你要跟迈达斯打？
You want to fight Midas?
五万保证金 赢家通吃！
Fifty thousand guaranteed, winner takes all.
- 五万？真的 五万？- 不开玩笑！
Fifty? Really, 50? Now you're talking.
等一下 听我的 不 考虑一下！
Listen, listen. No, look.
- 听我说一下！ - 等我一下
- Listen! - Give me a sec.
我们最好挑一些卡片上的对手 赚点现金离开这里
We should take an undercard fight, make a little cash and get out of here!
首先 不是“我们”
First, there is no "we."
第二 他会碾碎迈达斯 我可以赚一大笔
Second, he's going to crush Midas, and I'm going to make real cash!
我们会打败迈达斯的！
We'll take Midas!
今晚 我们的压轴！
Tonight, our main event
特别的金色血液的杀手
features the gold-blooded killer!
像庞克的痞子
This pimped-out punk
痛苦的制造者
is programmed for pain!
让我们欢迎神奇的迈达斯
I give to you the mighty Midas!
对抗者是...
Against a bot
曾经出现在世界大赛决赛的大男孩
who ran with the big boys in the WRB!
他刚结束全世界之旅 刚回到家的
He's been on an exile tour overseas, but now he's back home,
而且已经准备好要制造很多的噪音
and he's ready to make some noise!
好久不见的...
Take your first look in a long time
大声公
at Noisy Boy!
撞击宫殿！
Crash Palace,
谁已经准备好要开始大撞击了？
who's ready for some destruction?!
让我们开始赚大钱了 来吧！
Let's make some money! Come on!
现在 迈达斯对抗大声公
We have Midas against Noisy Boy.
大声公对抗马达斯
Noisy Boy against Midas.
你们等这个压轴等了一整晚 就在撞击宫殿！
You've been waiting all night for this match up, Crash Palace!
右拳半月弯刀！
Scimitar right!
你有看到吗？
Did you see that?
太简单了 钱真好赚 整晚都是这样！
Easy money, easy money all night. All night long!
赶快起来！ 还没有结束！来吧！
Come on! It's not over yet. Let's go!
面拳齐射！ ！交火！
Skull salvo! Firefight!
- 是的！ 上吧 制造噪音吧！！ - 你说卡片 是吗？
- Yeah! Go, Noisy! - Undercard, huh?
激波拳
Shockfist!
来吧！幕府三连击！
Get in there. Shogun Trinity!
干掉他！重力拳 直捣面门
Let's finish him. Gravity Slam, Uptown!
真TMD疯了！
This son-of-a-bitch is crazy!
金属的世仇 来吧！
Full Metal Feud! Bring it!
左拳！ 痛苦的革命者！
Southpaw! Pain Revolution!
让我给你一个礼物
I got something for you.
你敢逃开？你没有办法躲开！
Don't you run from me! You can't run from me!
站起来
Get up!
犯规了
That's illegal!
这是地下拳击 没有规则的
This is the underworld. There are no rules!
现在我们看迈达斯发飙了
Now we're seeing the Midas touch.
不 手举起来！
No. Hands up!
回到角落来 婊子 像男人一样大口喘气
Get back in that corner, bitch, and take this whooping like a man!
他要被干掉了...
He's getting killed in there!
用耳机组 告诉它怎么做！
It's a headset! You talk into it and you tell him what to do!
恐惧盾牌！
Panic Shield!
对了 对了 一二组合拳！
That's it. One-Two Overlord!
不 不 粉碎拳
No, no. Shatter Punch!
- 五连击 - 尝尝这个
- Five Recall! - Get some!
贾布 贾布！
Jab, jab!
右环拳！
Right roundhouse!
大声公是不是刚刚把它的机油溅到马达斯脸上？
Did he just spit his juice in Midas's face?
千万不可把机油溅到马达斯脸上
No, you did not spit in Midas's face!
让我们狂欢吧 撞击宫殿！
It's party time now, Crash Palace!
用你的左拳！
Use your left!
大声公试着用一只手来对抗
Noisy's trying to do something with his one arm!
但是迈达斯夹住了他！然后好好的教训他！
But Midas pins him, and Daddy goes to work!
不 不 起来！
No, no! Get up!
吃这个！
Get some!
移动！ 离开角落！
Move! Get out of the corner!
迈达斯！迈达斯！迈达斯！
Midas! Midas! Midas!
有人已经准备好送上卡布奇诺了！
Somebody's ready to serve up a decappuccino!
我要送你一个大礼 准备好了？
I got something for you! You ready?
晚安！迈达斯的最后一击！
Good night! That's a home run for Midas.
再见吧 大声公！
And so long to Noisy Boy.
太逊了 你饿了吗？
That sucked. You hungry?
我救回了大声公的声控控制面板
I saved what's left of Noisy's voice recognition board.
除了那个以外 已经变垃圾了 我要再找一个新机器人
Other than that, he's trash. I got to get a new robot together.
我需要一个主机 什么？
I need to find a mainframe. What?
- 我不喜欢汉堡 - 什么样的小孩不喜欢汉堡？
- I hate hamburgers. - What kid hates burgers?
好吧 我可以多吃一些 这个给你喝
Fine. More for me. Here, drink this.
你根本不该参加那场打斗的
You never should have taken that fight.
真的？真的？多谢你 天才！
Really? Really? Thanks, genius.
你总是那么的冲动吗？
Do you even think about the stuff you do before you do it?
你根本不知道怎么战斗
You had no idea how to fight that fight.
你知道的组合拳码根本不到一半
Those combination codes, you didn't know what half of them even meant.
你的狂妄自大害的它的屁股被踢成二半
You threw them in there cocky and half-assed.
- 你根本没有给他机会 - 大声公没有那么棒！
- You never gave him a chance. - He wasn't that good.
大声公是最好的机器人
Noisy Boy was a great robot.
曾经是 曾经是 大声公以前是很好 以前是
Was. Was a great robot back in the League, back in the day.
但是看看周围 这里是伟大的机器人毁掉的坟场
But look around you. This place is where once great robots go to die.
那就丢掉它？
So throw him away.
这就是你 是吧？你不需要的 就丢掉？
That's what you do, right? Anything you don't need you throw away.
哇
Wow.
这会是漫长的一夜
It's been a long night.
如果你要在里面睡 闭嘴 上车！
If you want to sleep indoors tonight, shut up and get in the truck.
不要这样看着我 上车！
Don't look at me like that way. Get in the truck!
他们花400买大声公的头
They gave me 400 for his head.
你坐好 我要去找一些零件！
You stay put. I'm going to look for parts.
我也要去 那个饮料让我很兴奋
I'm coming with you. That drink has my heart pounding.
如果我自己坐在车里 我的头会炸掉
If I sit in this truck by myself, my head will explode.
随便你 但是要跟好
Whatever. Just keep up.
真背
Crap.
退后
Stay back.
好了 跟上！
All right, keep up.
这个探照灯是定时的 你只要知道时间间隔就好
These searchlights are automated, but you got to time them right,
所以跟紧
so stay close.
那就对了！
It's all right.
来吧 快点！
Come on, come on.
- 我们会被抓啦！ - 来啦！
- We're going to get caught. - Come on.
慢一点 小心一点
Easy, easy. Easy, easy.
快一点 下来这里 快快快
Quick, quick. Down in here! Go, go, go!
机器人都在东边 我们要快一点通过这里
Robots are on the east side. We got to be quick in here.
过了这里就没有探照灯了 快 跑！
Once we're through here, there's no more searchlights. Quick! Go!
- 到了 - 我们要找什么？
- Here it is. - What are we looking for?
可以组合机器人的任何东西
Anything I could use to put a fighting bot together.
- 嗨 你看 - 什么？
- Hey, look. - What?
太小了
It's so small.
耶 那个比你还要老
Yeah. That's before your time.
那个是第一代的战斗机器人
That's a Generation One, the very first fighting bot.
他们被造的很像人类 越像越好
They wanted them to look like us. The more human, the better.
没想到变得那么快 把这个放进拖车
Crazy how quick everything changed. Put that in the cart.
- 什么改变了？- 好问题 人类的拳击
- What changed? - A good question. Human boxing.
- 已经退流行了 - 为什么？
- It just faded. - Why?
因为金钱改变了一切 人们要更血腥 更好看
Because the money moved on. People wanted more carnage, more show.
可以综合巴西柔术 格雷西 日式忍者术
You had the whole Brazilian underground, the Gracies, the Machados,
泰拳...几千种不同的武术糅合在一起
jiu-jitsu, Muay Thai, and a thousand styles in between.
全部在水泥地上的重击
Full-on ground-and-pound.
- 看看这个 - 这是什么？
- Look at this. - What's that?
我也不知道
I don't know.
不错的零件
Not bad. Good spot.
如果还是一个拳手 人类的身体
You still had human fighters, human bodies,
你没有办法给人们他们想要的
so you couldn't give the people what they really wanted:
真相是 没有围栏的暴力 这就是人们想要的
True, no-holds-barred violence.
所以符合逻辑的下一步
The next logical step,
把人们移开 让机器来自相残杀
get the humans out of there and let the machines kill each other.
你会想念真正的拳击吗？
Do you miss it?
- 拳击 你想念吗？- 小心
- Boxing. Do you miss it? - Careful.
什么？我想知道
What? I want to know.
小心一点 你下面是个峭壁
Careful, you're on a cliff.
那下面很深 如果你掉下去 你就绝对...
That's a long way down. If you fell, you'd definitely...
Charlie 救我！
Charlie, help me!
Charlie！
Charlie!
- Charlie！ - Max！
- Charlie! - Max! Max!
Max！
Max!
- 不要动！ - 有一个机器人的手勾住了我
- Try not to move! - I'm on some sort of robot arm.
等一下！ 不要动 千万不要动 把手伸过来 慢一点 轻一点
Wait! Just easy, easy. Give me your hand. Nice and easy.
要很慢很慢 很好 不要看下面 看着我 看着我 ！
Very slowly. Good. Don't look down. Look at me. Look at me.
就是这样！ 我抓住你了！不用怕了 我抓住你了
That's it! I've got you! You don't have to be scared. I got you!
- 下面好深啊 - 没问题了 我抓住你了！
- It's so far! - It's OK. I got you.
把手给我 慢一点 轻一点
Give me your other hand. Nice and slow.
只要动你的手 把你的手伸过来 慢慢的 递过来
Just give me your other hand very slowly. Reach back. Come on. Reach!
看着我 我们一起来
Look at me. We're going to do this together.
就是你跟我 看着我 对的！
You and me. Just look at me. That's it.
一 二 三！
One... two... three!
就是这样 我抓住你了 我抓住你了！
That's it. I got you! I got you. I got you. I got you.
你安全了 你安全了！
You're safe. You're safe.
没事了 我抓住你了
All right, I got you.
- 你还好吗？- 还好
- You all right? - Yeah.
过来这里 慢一点 慢一点
Come here. Easy. Easy.
你还好吗？
You all right?
- 你还好吗？- 是的
- You all right? - Yeah.
我告诉你很危险了
I told you it was dangerous.
小心一点 我们还在悬崖边上
Careful. We're still on the edge here.
Charlie 我看到一整个机器人了
Charlie, I think there's a whole robot in there.
那又怎么样？走吧！来吧
So what? Let's go. Come on.
我要带走它 他救了我一命！
I'm taking him with me. He saved my life.
他没有救你一命 是我救得 走吧！
He did not save your life. I saved your life. Let's go.
把推车推到边上 我会用卷线拉上去！
Just bring the cart to the edge. I'll use the winch to get him out.
你要捡这个垃圾 你自己推车 我不玩了
You want that piece of junk? You get the cart yourself. I'm through here.
这是大声公剩下的零件？
This is what's left of Noisy Boy?
是的
That's it.
他的头已经变成撞击宫殿大门上的装潢了
His head does make a nice addition to the front of the Crash Palace.
- 正经一点 - 我们再做一个机器人
- It's not funny. - Let's get a robot, you and me.
好点子 只不过你破产了 我也快了
Good idea. You're broke. I'm almost there myself.
- 你搞砸了你最好的一次机会了 - 我们可以一起做出来的
- You destroyed the best shot you had. - We'll put one together.
你是那么聪明 这里又有那么多好零件
You're brilliant at this. There's good stuff here.
- 这里什么都没有 - 有啊 你看！
- There's nothing here. - There is. Look.
这些都是垃圾... 垃圾
All your junk is... it's junk.
你甚至已经没有办法参加比赛了
You're not even in the game any more.
- 都是垃圾 - 我知道了 都是垃圾
- It's all garbage. - I heard you. It's garbage.
不要对我大声
Don't get loud with me.
- 这是你自己的麻烦 - 你这是什么意思？
- You're your problem. - What's that supposed to mean?
我已经在这里帮你很长一段时间了
I have been here for you a long time.
台上 台下 还有这个物价上升 已经烦够了
In the ring, out of the ring, and the whole ugly spiral down, and I'm tired.
我父亲投资所有的财产支持你的拳击 我们爱...
My father invested everything he had in your fight career. We loved...
他把你当成自己亲人来照顾 这里是他的家
He loved you like family. And this is his home.
我努力的维持住这个家 让他不要破碎！
I'm just trying not to let it die. That's my plan.
你呢？
What's yours?
你放弃了 是吧？
You're done, right?
你终于放弃了？因为我真的TMD确定 Charlie
You're finally done? Because I sure as hell am, Charlie.
我什么都没有了
I got nothing left.
好吧
All right.
或许这里面还有点东西
Maybe there's something here.
昨天晚上小鬼带回来的机器人 你可以帮我看看吗？
This robot the kid brought in last night. Would you look at it for me?
拜托！
Please?
我从没有看过这一型的机器人 它应该是第二代的
I've never seen anything like it before. He's Generation Two, but barely.
我找到一个适合他的电池 然后我用旧型的G-2 无线连上他
I found a power cell that fits him, and I hooked him up to this old G-2 remote.
你可以让他动起来 但是他还是垃圾
You can move him around, but he's crap.
或许我可以安排几个拳击表演 赚个几千块
Maybe I can get a sparring gig for him, make a few hundred bucks.
住手
Stop.
这是我的机器人
It's my robot!
它花了我大半夜 辛苦的把它挖出来 他是我的
It took me half the night dragging him out of there. He's mine.
他是你的？但是用来修好他的零件是我的！
He's yours? Yeah. But the parts we're putting in him are mine!
你们二个白痴先不要吵 看看通电以后是什么样子
You idiots should see if he powers up before you fight over him.
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
小心一点 退后
Watch out. Stay back.
看来它有一个映射功能 那是很罕见的
Looks like he's got a shadow function. That's pretty rare.
他可以模仿你的动作 记忆起来
He can mime your movements and store them in memory.
- 有没有什么是我们可以利用的？- 我看是没有
- Is there anything here we could use? - Not much.
哪里有个水桶...
There's a bucket...
有个我用来洗车的水桶
There's a bucket I use to wash the truck.
用来把它洗干净 它闻起来像大便
Use it and clean him up. He smells like crap.
也把你自己洗一洗 你闻起来也像大便
Wash yourself off, too, while you're at it. You stink.
我把它调到最基本的无线功能
I switched him to remote. It's pretty basic.
用绳子拴住他 带着他
Just use the toggles here to steer him and walk him.
- 你玩电动游戏 是吧？- 当然
- You play video games, right? - Of course.
一样的概念 只是它是个一千磅的机器人
Same idea, only this one's a thousand-pound robot.
酷
Cool.
"Atom"
"Atom."
他的名字叫“ATOM” 我们可以让他参加格斗吗？
His name is Atom. Can we get him a fight?
他不是战斗型的机器人
I don't think he was ever a boxing robot.
他是第二代的 2014年建造的 用来表演拳击的
He's a G-2, built in early 2014. He was a sparring bot.
他们是建造来镜像...
They must have built robots like this one
其他战斗型的机器人
that could mirror the fighting style of any other robot.
好的 我们可以让他参加格斗？
OK, so can we get him a fight?
你有没有在听？它是表演机器人
Are you not listening? He's a sparring bot.
它是可以承受很多撞击 但是承受不了真正的大力一击
Built to take a lot of hits, but never dishing out any real punishment.
你可以当成零件卖掉它
You could always sell him off for parts.
- 我们可不可以让他参加格斗？- "你为什么要让他参加格斗？"
- Can't you get him a fight? - "Why can't you get him a fight?"
天啊 你就是不放弃是吧？
God, you don't quit, do you?
你要我帮他放到格斗场 格斗祭 然后害死他？
You want me to put him in some bottom-rung scrap-fest to the death?
我看你在撞击宫殿里面是那么害怕
I saw how scared you were at Crash Palace.
可以让你参加格斗的地方会让你吓到尿裤子
The places that would let you fight this robot would make you pee your pants.
好极了 带他去格斗
Excellent. Get him a fight.
顽固的孩子
Stubborn kid.
惊喜吗？
Surprise, surprise.
我们散散步
Let's take a walk.
你听得懂我说的吗？
Can you understand me?
别担心 我会保密的
Don't worry. Your secret's safe with me.
你认识Charlie非常久了
You've known Charlie a long time.
很久了 我们一起在健身房长大的
Too long. We both kind of grew up in this gym.
我父亲是他的教练
My dad, he trained him.
那是他们 那是Charlie
That's them. That's Charlie.
- 他是什么样子？- 当拳手的时候？
- What was he like? - As a boxer?
- 年轻的时候 - 他很不简单
- As anything. - He was something.
他很瘦 强硬
He was lean, tough.
永不放弃 不会恐惧
No quit, no fear.
来这里 我让你看看
Come here. I want to show you something.
给你看看2007年在凤凰城的报导
I have this newspaper article from Phoenix 2007
当Charlie跟尼克康迪决战的时候 那是他的巅峰
when Charlie fought Nico Tandy, the top contender.
你也有看那场拳赛？
You were at the Nico Tandy fight?
有的 Charlie本来只是热身的对手 应该是很容易被揍扁的
I was. Charlie was supposed to be a warm-up fight, an easy win.
尼克本来是应该连汗都不流一滴的
Nico wasn't even supposed to break a sweat, but...
但是Charlie没那么想 他一步一步的逼近尼克
nobody told Charlie that, so he just kept coming and coming at him.
结果你知道吗？
Check this out.
这就是Charlie
That's Charlie.
一开始尼克不敢相信这个无名小卒会那么有胆识
First, Nico couldn't believe the balls on this nobody.
但是Charlie决不后退 尼克开始害怕了
But Charlie kept coming, and that's when Nico looked scared.
- 真的？- 是真的
- Really? - Really.
变成Charlie在玩弄尼克
He was toying with Nico.
这个世界排名第二名的拳手
The top contender, number two in the world,
Charlie像飞舞的蝴蝶玩弄着他
and Charlie was dancing with him.
Charlie整晚的脚步就像漂浮在拳击台上那么顺
Charlie was floating inches off the canvas that night.
就像鬼魂一样 尼克根本看不到他
He was like a ghost. Nico couldn't even see him.
我看得到
I could.
脚步是那么完美
He was beautiful.
就是那么完美
后来呢？Charlie击败尼克了？
So what happened? Did Charlie beat Nico Tandy?
不 尼克在第12回合揍扁了我 二次！
No, Nico Tandy put me on my ass in the 12th round. Twice.
第二次倒下 我被打晕了 再也站不起来！
Second time for good. Lights out.
当时计分板上 你是领先的！
You were ahead on the scorecards
- 一直到第12回合 - 结果第12回合 尼克击倒我
- going into the 12th round. - Nico Tandy rung my bell
后面三年他都是世界拳王
and went on to be the undefeated world champ for the next three years.
- 他击倒你？- 是的 还有很多人击倒我
- He knocked you out? - Yeah. So did a lot of guys.
你也击倒很多人啊！
You knocked a lot of guys out, too.
- 24 场19胜 大概是这样 - 但是胜场都是击倒胜
- 24 and 19. It's not exactly a career. - But every fight a knockout.
- 是的 - 赢或输 没有平手
- Yeah. - Win or lose, fight's not over
- 直到一方倒下 - 直到一方倒下
- till someone's on the mat. - Till someone's on the mat.
- 你父亲教我的 - 没错 他教你的
- Your old man taught me that. - Damn straight he taught you that.
- 你还有跟谁比过？- 去收拾你的东西
- Who else did you fight? - Go get your stuff together.
我收好了 你有任何排名吗？
I don't need to. Did you fight for the title?
你还要再收拾！我们再一个小时就出发了 去收拾！
Yeah, you do. We leave in an hour. Go.
哇 还你！
Wow. Here.
你留着吧
Keep it.
- 谢谢！ - 不客气！
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
我喜欢Max
I like that kid.
他也喜欢你
He likes you.
- 我昨天晚上说的... - 不 一切尽在不言中
- What I said yesterday was... - No, nothing more to say.
我今天晚上会到亚特兰大市
I'm heading off to Atlanta tonight
看看可不可以找到合伙人 募点钱 买个新的...
to see if I can get a partner or raise money to get a new bot.
这是你想要的吧 ？我走？
That's what you wanted, right? Me gone?
是啊 这是我想要的
Yeah, that's what I wanted.
好的
OK.
翻译：闲闲的猛男 校对：目前没有
“百丽来电”--拒接来电
赶快看
Look.
拳王在这里 宙斯在这里比赛
The champ is here. Zeus is here.
耶
Yeah.
没有人能够跟这个怪兽打二个回合
Zeus! No one has ever gone two rounds with this monster. Two rounds!
拳王交出他的冠军腰带 准备保卫战
The champ puts his Real Steel world championship belt on the line tonight.
可能他今天晚上会遇到一场真正的较量
He just may have a real fight on his hands.
最后 还是宙斯赢了 最强的终极格斗机器人 晚安！
Zeus, greatest robot boxer of all time. Ever. End of story. Good night!
- 太酷了 真是太酷了 - 你说什么？
- So cool. It's so cool. - What?
来吧
Come on.
听好 我要去找芬尼
Listen up. I got to go find Finn.
你要乖乖呆在这一区
I want you to stay in this area.
不要挡路 拳王来了 让开路
Out of the way. Champ coming through. Zeus coming through.
走开走开 拳王要过来了
Move, move. Champ coming through.
法拉兰蔻娃 宙斯是属于他父亲的
Farra Lemkova, daughter behind the father/daughter Zeus team.
大家说你父亲只是出钱 你才是宙斯的领导者
They say your father's the money and you are the mind behind Zeus.
你太客气了
You're very kind,
但是我要提醒你 松本先生才是宙斯真正的领导者！
but I assure you, the mind behind Zeus belongs to the great Tak Mashido.
是什么吸引了这个隐居的天才 这个天才神童
What did it take to lure the reclusive genius, former boy wonder
然后投入这个最重要的大赛的格斗机器人
and arguably the most important bot designer in the history of the sport
为什么有办法让他再出山？
out of retirement?
为什么你不自己问问他？
Why don't you ask him yourself?
宙斯是不是松本先生最伟大的设计？
Is this Tak Mashido's greatest creation?
宙斯是不断的可以在战斗中自主学习型的机器人
Zeus is autonomous and constantly evolving during a fight.
他有非常强的适应能力
With his adaptive operating system,
他可以随时的辨识对手的战斗模式 即时更新自己的模式
he recognizes patterns and rewrites his fight code instantaneously.
对于我及乔派克的理解 你是说宙斯......
For myself and Joe Sixpack out there, are you saying that Zeus?
我是说不管在场上发生什么事...
I'm saying that no matter what happens in that ring...
...结果都是一样的
the result of any fight is inevitable.
宙斯只会...
What Zeus sees...
...神挡杀神 鬼挡杀鬼！
he kills.
太好了
Sweet.
我绝对不会投资你的生意
I'm never going into business with you.
我只需要一点小帮助
I just need a break here.
你不是还有一台旧卡车 不是还有机器人在里面
You got that old bot truck out there. You always got something in there.
我有一个表演用的机器人 不值钱的
I got an old sparring bot, ain't worth the paint left on it.
我现在还能怎么办？
What am I supposed to do with that?
带他到动物园 动物园明天有比赛
The Zoo. Take him to the Zoo. They fight there tomorrow.
在动物园我只会被干掉
Even I wouldn't be caught dead at the Zoo.
我只需要借一点钱
I just need a little loan.
什么？
What?
- Charlie 你是认真的吗？- 借一笔钱
- You're serious, Charlie? - A loan.
几百 几千 都可以 只要你愿意借
Couple hundred. Few hundred. Whatever you got.
我知道你有钱可以借给我
You know I'm good for it.
我很了解你 老兄 我很喜欢你的人
I know you, and as much as I like you, dude...
...只是 你实在是一个不会赌的人 兄弟
you're a bad bet, brother.
太好了 耶
Right, yeah.
你有没有看到？艾克洛德只剩下那一半...
Did you see that? That's what's left of Axelrod.
你跑去哪里了？不是告诉你不要乱跑
Where you been? I told you to stay put.
你应该要看看宙斯 太神奇了！
You should have seen him. Zeus was, like, amazing!
- 神奇 阿？- 不敢相信 耶
- Amazing, huh? - Unbelievable, yeah.
他接二连三的打击艾克洛德 很快的 太厉害了
He was just peppering Axelrod with punches, but so fast. It was incredible.
艾克洛德一拳也没有打中宙斯 也撑不过一个回合
Axelrod didn't even land a punch. He didn't even survive the first round.
你以为拳击就是这样？
Is that what you think boxing is?
宙斯的比赛都是“安排”好的
Zeus beating up some piece of steel that they feed him?
艾克洛德只是一块铁 拳赛已经变得是那么低劣了
Axelrod's not just some piece of steel. And that is what boxing is now.
你连这个都不知道 我喜爱这个比赛 而且我还是圈内人
Deal with it. And I love it, and I'm in it now.
你还在圈内？你跟你的旧第二代机器人？
You're in it now, are you? You and your G-2 sparring bot?
他很厉害的 帮我们安排比赛 你就会知道
He's more than that. If you'd get us a fight, you'd see.
好的 你很幸运 有个地方叫做野兽园
You're in luck, kid. There's a lovely place called the Zoo.
明天下午 你可以参加格斗
Tomorrow afternoon, you'll get your fight.
- 很好 - 然后我们就彻底完蛋了
- Great. - And it will be the end.
我告诉你我不喜欢汉堡
I told you I hate hamburgers!
是墨西哥卷饼啦
It's a burrito!
右上勾拳
Right uppercut.
左上勾拳
Left uppercut.
蹲低一点 举起你的双手
Bend your knees. Rise up with both hands.
再来一次 蹲下 举起你的双手
Again. Bend your knees. Rise up with both hands.
你这样一整晚？
You been up all night?
是的 我把它清理了一下
Yeah. I cleaned him up.
我用动作映射功能教他一点格斗技 然后同步到遥控器里面
I'm using shadow mode to program some fight moves and sync them to the remote.
是的 我看到你教他的双上击拳
Yeah. I saw that double-up punch you were showing him.
这是绝招
That's lethal stuff.
走吧 我们去格斗吧！
Let's do this.
吃早餐先吧
Let's do breakfast first.
你知道等下他就会被拆成碎片吧？
You know you're bringing him home in pieces, right?
等下你就知道
We'll see.
- 让我来！ - Charlie肯顿 这是马克思！
- Let me deal with this. - Charlie Kenton. This is Max.
首脑 叫我首脑
Kingpin. Call me Kingpin.
- 好吧！首脑 那么... - 一回合我们可以赚多少钱呢？
- All right, Kingpin, so... - How much a round?
我们正在巡回比赛
We on a field trip?
可以你可以跟我的机器人 Metro对打
All right. He can fight my robot Metro.
二分钟 一回合 一百元
I'll give you a hundred bucks for one two-minute round.
- 接受它 - 三百
- Take it. - Three hundred.
一百元 小男孩 给你一百元是为了Metro练练
One hundred. Baby boy, I'm going to give you $100 just to get in with Metro.
何不500元打二个回合？
How about 500 for two rounds?
二个回合？小鬼 你的机器人连一个回合都撑不过
Two rounds. Son, he ain't going to survive one round.
- 如果它可以呢？- 它没办法的
- What if he does? - He ain't.
让我们先假设它可以
Let's just say he does.
如果第一回合结束 他还能站着...
If he's still standing after one round...
...我就给你一千元
I'll give you a thousand bucks.
闭嘴！
Shut it!
但是如果他 我看是一定毁在那里 年轻人...
But if he dies in there, which he will, junior...
...剩下的零件都归我了
I get to keep what's left.
一百元的赌注就好...
Take the hundred.
没问题
Deal.
成局了 比赛开始！
We're on. We on!
走吧！
Let's go!
- 你应该接收100元的赌注的 - 我帮我们争取更好的 1000元
- You should have taken the hundred. - I got us a thousand.
是啊 如果它赢得了
Yeah, if he wins.
你要我来操作吗？
You want me to drive?
他是我的机器人 我自己操作！
He's my bot. I got this!
在这里的是真正的比赛 不是电动游戏
This ain't a video game. This is for real. Right here.
你不是说他会被拆碎？那谁操作有差吗？
You said he's coming home in pieces. What difference does it make?
好吧！随便你！
All right.
我来就好！
I got this.
开始吧 开始吧！
Let's get it on! Let's get it on!
让我们像在香港打乒乓球那样修理他吧！
Let's get it on like Ping-Pong in Hong Kong!
敲响铃声 敲铃吧！
Give me a bell! Give me a bell!
不要看着Atom注意你的对手
Don't watch Atom. Watch your opponent.
注意他的脚 他要用脚钉住你
Watch out for that foot. He's looking to pin you.
我告诉你要小心那个踩脚的贱招数
I told you to watch for that foot plant. Come on.
注意！大榔头要来了
Here comes the sledgehammer.
有没有看到？
Did you see that?
- 来吧！ 控制他！ - 不要吼他 控制好他
- Come on! Get him! - Don't yell at him, control him.
滑到右边 退后！
Slip right. Back step.
低头
Duck.
- 不客气 - 闭嘴！ 你在帮倒忙！
- You're welcome. - Shut up! You're not helping!
事实上 我认为我才对
Actually, I think I am.
后脑 你要快一点 移动快一点 屈膝
Backhand. You got speed on this guy. Just keep moving. Bob.
避开角落 不停移动 迂回前进
Slip out of that corner. Keep moving! Bob and weave!
就是这样！总算听懂我说的了
That's it! Now you're listening to me.
你的机器人真能挨揍 我告诉你 你的机器人很耐打
He can take a hit. I'll give you this. Your bot can take a hit.
你最好避开那个锁头 这个会对你是个大麻烦
You better slip that headlock. This ain't gonna end well for you.
我在躲！
I'm trying!
剩30秒！
Thirty seconds!
30... 半分钟！
Thirty... Half a minute.
半分钟！ 不停移动！ 不要停下来！
Half a minute! Keep moving! Just move!
只要再撑20秒
You've got 20 seconds!
- 再撑20秒就赚了1000元 让我来操作！ - 不要！
That's a thousand bucks. Twenty seconds. Let me take over!
移动 然后 移动！
Move, then. Move!
不会吧！
Come on.
起来 Atom 站起来 Atom
Get up, Atom. Get up, Atom.
跟我一起数！ 跟我一起数！ 1！
Count with me! Count with me! One!
- 起来！ - 你知道你是在对一个机器说话吧？
- Get up! - You know you're talking to a machine?
4 5 6！
Four! Five! Six!
起来 Atom！
Get up, Atom!
站起来了！ 站起来了！
All the way up! All the way up!
耶！ 耶！
Yes! Yes!
我来搞定！
I'm going to fix it!
我来搞定 来吧！现在！
I'm going to fix it! Come on, now.
- 这里有一千元... - 耶 一千
- This thousand bucks... - Yeah, thousand.
全压 压他打不完第二回合！
Double or nothing he can't make another round.
- 耶 不用了 谢谢！ - 接受！全压 再奥下去！
- Yeah, thanks anyway. - Deal. Double or nothing.
小男孩说了！ 再来！ 开始咯！
Baby boy said it! We're back on! We on!
你疯了吗？你刚刚丢了1000元？
Are you crazy? You threw away a thousand bucks!
他只是勉强支持住
He can barely stand up in there.
我真的很需要这笔钱
Look. I really need the money.
我知道 我来处理！
I know. Let's work.
天啊！
Jesus.
- 小心！踩脚贱招！ - 我看到了！
- Watch that. Watch that. - I got that.
- 我控制住了 - 它的系统崩溃了
- I got it. - That's a system failure!
- 失控了！ - 他要倒下了！
- I don't got it. - He's going down.
- 耶！ - 不！
- Yes! - No!
开始倒数！
Start the count!
1 2 3！
One! Two! Three!
4 5 6 7！
Four! Five! Six! Seven!
8 9！
Eight! Nine!
10！
Ten!
你办到了！ 我们办到了！哇！
You did it! We did it! Wow!
该走了 来吧 带上你的机器人！
Time to go. Come on. Grab your robot.
我知道 我知道 我知道！
I know, I know! I know! I know!
首脑 付钱吧！
Kingpin, pay up.
好吧！好吧！好吧！我知道！我知道！
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I know, I know, I know.
- 我们赢了！ - 走吧！赶快走！
- We owned! - Let's go. Come on, come on.
- 耶？- 我有没有帮你安排过比赛？
- Yeah? - Have I got a fight for you.
一场比赛四千 如果赢了七千 周六晚上！
Saturday night. Guaranteed four grand. Seven if he wins.
四千？没问题 我们走吧！
Four grand? You're on. Let's go!
翻译：闲闲的猛男 校对：目前没有
百丽 是我 Atom赢了
Bailey, it's me. He won.
你相信吗？小鬼的机器人真的赢了！
Can you believe that? The kid's robot actually won.
我知道！
I know.
高兴吗？天啊！耶！
Happy? Oh, my God. Yeah.
Atom被揍了 被揍的很惨！
He's been bit. He's been bit real bad.
但是...
Anyway...
我只是希望让你知道
I just wanted you to know.
刺拳 刺拳 勾拳！
Jab, jab, hook.
我认为你还要移动你的双腿
I think you have to move your feet.
你的双腿
Your feet. Feet.
漂亮的动作 小鬼！
Nice moves, kid.
你整晚没有睡？
How long you been out here?
你看看！
Check it out.
我整晚没睡做了一件了不起的事
I just spent the night doing something I think is amazing.
完全不可思议的事 然后搞定了
Incredibly amazing. If it works, you know?
- 你知道他的遥控器很脏了 - 是的
- You know his remote was spotty? - Yeah.
我丢掉了 不用了 我们不需要了！
I killed it. Got rid of it. We don't need it any more.
不会吧你？
How did you?
我想要重新再输入！
I had to start over.
所以我用突击者号的中心控制板
But I was able to use the spin frame from Ambush
然后把大声公的声控板移过去
and take the circuitry sleeve out of Noisy Boy,
成功了！
and it works.
他现在资料库空了 但是更好用了！
He knows nothing, but it works. It really, really works.
什么更好用了？
What works?
让我打开给你看！
I got to turn it on.
左刺拳 右上钩拳！
Left jab, right uppercut!
日式！
Japan!
你把大声公的声控模式移植到Atom身上？
You put Noisy's voice recognition into Atom?
- 非常聪明 小鬼！ - 聪明？
- Pretty smart, kid. - Smart?
我是天才！
It could be genius!
那个是世界上最聪明的事
It could be the most incredible thing in the history of the entire world!
不要那么兴奋 你把所有的汽水都喝完了？
Easy there, chief. Did you drink all these sodas?
我喝了一些 我需要你教Atom拳击
I might have had a few. I need you to teach him to box.
你不要开玩笑了？他没有那个级数去使出大声公的组合动作
Are you kidding me? He's not advanced enough to handle Noisy's voice command.
所以他需要你的动作 你的组合
So he needs your moves. Your commands.
- 从脚步动作开始 - 别想了
- Start over from the ground up. - Forget it.
你曾经是一个拳击手
You were a boxer.
昨天你在野兽园 可以清清楚楚的研判他们的动作
Yesterday at the Zoo, you could see things happen before they even happened.
我已经很久没有打拳了 也不想再打了！
I haven't boxed in a long time. I'm not starting now.
- 那谁来教它打拳？- 你就教的不错啊！
- Who's going to teach him to fight? - You're doing fine.
不需要我来教！对不起！
You don't need me. Sorry.
但是话说回来 那个舞步很酷
That was really cool, though, that dance.
我们周六晚上应该跳一下那个舞
You should do that on Saturday night.
- 不要取笑我 - 我是说真格的！
- Don't make fun of me. - I'm serious.
在比赛前 在你们进入场地的时候 你们应该跳的1
Before the fight, when you guys take the ring, you should do it.
我才不想在拳击观众面前跳舞的
There's no way I'm dancing with a robot in front of a boxing crowd.
不会吧你？这一切都只是场秀！
Are you kidding me? This is just a show.
人们想看到一些从所未有的
People want to see something they've never seen.
你看 所有伟大的拳手！
Look. You think of all the greats.
像阿里 甜心雷 雷金王子 加玛...
Think Ali, Sugar Ray, Prince Rakim, Gammer,
他们都有他们的措号
they all had their nicknames.
他们都有天分 特质...
They had their personae. They all had flair.
你呢？虽然你的机器人不起眼 但是如果你会跳舞 这就是你的特质
Now you? You might not have much robot, but with that dance, you got flair.
而且 你是小孩 人们总是喜欢小孩玩意的
Plus, you're a kid. People love that kid thing.
- 你几岁？九岁？十岁？- 我十一岁了
- What are you? Like nine? Ten? - I'm 11.
你确定？
Are you sure you're 11?
是的 我确定我十一岁！
Yes. I'm sure I'm 11.
不管了 重点是人们想看到这个
Anyway, the point is people want to see that.
你不是故意搞我吧？
You're really not messing with me?
我没搞你 观众会喜欢这个的！
I am not messing with you. They're going to love it.
- 酷 - 但是...
- Cool. - But...
- 什么？- 你也要帮我
- What? - I won't do it unless you help me.
你要我一起跳 我不跳 你就不跳？
I can't dance. You're on your own there.
不是 是教拳击
No. Boxing.
- 噢 我懂了！ - 我来编程序
- Oh, I see. - I program the robot.
- 你来教他拳击 - 然后你跳舞
- You teach him to box. - And you dance.
然后你来跳舞！
And you dance.
- 好吗？- 好！
- Yeah. - Yeah?
一言为定
Deal.
那样会很酷的
It's going to be cool.
很好
Nice.
你的对手都是比较高的 所以你要打高一点！
You're going to be punching guys bigger. You're going to have to punch up.
对了 就是这样！
That's it.
很好！
Nice.
你也是老骨头一把了？
You, too, old man?
来吧！让我们好好锻炼！
Come on. Let's get to work.
很好 再做一次
Nice! Let's do that again.
很好！三连击组合！
Nice. Three-punch combo.
组合拳！
Combo.
再一次 再一次！
Again. Again.
快一点 再快一点 很好！
Faster. Faster. Nice.
你甚至不用调呼吸 很好 我喜欢！
You're not even out of breath. I like it.
让我们看看你的动作！
Let's see how you move.
很好
That's good.
退后几步！ 左勾拳 左勾拳！
Step around! Left hook! Left hook!
就是这样 每次都是
That's it. Every time.
上勾拳
Upper cut!
很好的比赛 各位
Great fight, fellas.
1055频率 WRUT 家庭卫星机器人格斗频道
105.5, WRUT, the satellite home of robot boxing.
第二个扣应 你有什么要分享的？
Caller two, what do you got for me?
你有没有听过一个小个头的机器人 叫做Atom的？
Have you heard about this little bot out there, his name is Atom?
噢 是的
Oh, yeah.
我们一群朋友昨天晚上有看到 他会跳舞
My buddies and I saw him the other night, and he dances.
- 你是说 "舞蹈"？- 是的 就是舞蹈
- Did you say "dances"? - You heard me.
他在比赛前都会跟个小男孩一起表演舞蹈
He dances pre-fight with this little kid,
观众都看疯了 乐疯了！
and the crowd went nuts for these two.
先不讨论哪些花招小玩意
You put the gimmick aside for a second,
我手里有份他打败的人的名单
and I'm holding here a list of the bots he's beaten.
赵 华尔街 独眼Jack 一个个都是不好惹的是吧！
Chaos. Wall Street. One-Eyed Jack. No slouches on that list, right?
Atom把它们统统打败了
Atom's fought them all, beat them all.
Atom很快 他躲过这些大家伙的绝招 不可思议是吧！
This bot is fast! He escapes shots from these bigger bots, it's insane!
不用怀疑 听众们一定会记得这个名字
No doubt. I'm telling you, listeners, remember this name:
Atom 没错 A-T-O-M 这个机器人值得一看
Atom. That's right, A-T-O-M. This bot is one to watch.
- 很好的格斗 先生 - 谢谢！谢谢！
- Awesome fight, sir. - Thanks, thanks.
好比赛！
Great fight.
- 你们的表演很精彩 - 谢谢！
- You guys put on a good show. - Thanks.
我们想邀请你们参加我们的比赛
We'd like to invite you to fight on our card,
维吉尼亚州 史倍壮中心 底特律 周五晚上
Virgin America Spectrum Detroit, Friday night.
好的 那是WRB...这不是职业比赛？
Right. That's a WRB... That's a League fight.
没错 你怎么说 老弟 你准备好了吗？
Damn right it is. What do you say, fellas? You ready for the show?
当然 耶
Heck, yeah.
这是不计名次的 但是还是职业级的
It's the undercard, but it's still a League fight.
我要你放松一点 平常心
I just want you to be relaxed. I want you to be relaxed.
不要祛场 不要给我那个疑惑的表情
No freaking out. Don't get all freaky-deaky on me.
如果你疑惑了 你会被修理的很惨
You go freaky-deaky, this whole thing can go south.
不管怎么样 享受比赛 享受乐趣 不要紧张
Whatever you do, have fun, have fun. You got to have fun, you understand me?
我们来到这里已经很不容易的 祛场会搞砸一切的
We've come too far to get out there and freak out and blow this whole thing.
一切会很有趣的 千万不要祛场！
We're going to have fun, and we're going to not freak out!
我们好好地放松心情 好好的修理对手一顿
We're going to stay loose, and we're just going to bam him.
这是我一辈子的梦想 我们将要参加...
I've spent my whole life waiting to get here. We're going to...
告诉你 相信我 千万不要祛场 听到了吗？
I tell you what. Trust me when I say no freaking out. You got it?
- 听到了 - 很好
- I got it. - Good.
你们被邀请到连科娃贵宾室 请跟我来
You have been invited to Lemkova Suite. Follow me, please.
你说什么？再说一遍
What was that? One more time.
连科娃贵宾室 宙斯的贵宾室
Lemkova Suite. Zeus Suite.
当然 让我们一起到拳王的贵宾室
Sure. Yeah. Let's head up to the champ's suite. Sure.
哇
Wow.
- 先生们 我是法罗 兰蔻娃 - 你好 我是Charlie肯顿 这是...
- Gentlemen, I'm Farra Lemkova. - Yeah. I'm Charlie Kenton, and...
当然还有松本先生
And this, of course, is Tak Mashido.
老天爷！是松本先生
Holy shit. It's Tak Mashido.
我知道你们今晚有一场重要的比赛 所以我就直接了当说了
I know you have a very important fight tonight, so I'll get right to it.
那个动作我喜欢 很漂亮的动作 所以... (Charlie已经语无伦次了）
It's a little far from the action for my liking. It's nice. I like it, though.
漂亮的相片... 哇！非常漂亮
Very nicely... Wow. That's a great shot.
看看这个 你要个签名吗？你介意吗？
Look at that. You want an autograph? Would you mind?
我想买你们的机器人
I'd like to buy your robot.
他对我们是一个很好的前场表演机器人 所以我愿意付你们
He'd be useful sparring bot for Zeus. And for that I'm willing to pay.
二十万
$200,000.
- 没问题 - 我不要卖
- Done. - He's not for sale.
- 当然要 我们绝对可以... - Atom是不卖的
- Of course he is. We can definitely... - He's not for sale.
你们还有十五分钟要对上双子星
You are 15 minutes away from getting in the ring with Twin Cities,
一个邪恶的职业机器人
a vicious League bot.
所以我的报价在铃声前才有效
So, to be clear, my offer stands until the starting bell.
好的 但是让我再说一遍 不卖！
OK. And just to be clear, he's not for sale!
现在不卖 以后也不卖
Not now, not ever.
给我一分钟想清楚 好吗！
Give me a minute to clear this up, OK?
松本 你好吗？Max！！慢一点！
Tak, how are you? Max!
聪明一点 我知道你很喜欢他
Be smart. I know you love him,
但是过二十分钟 它可能就毁了
but in 20 minutes there may be nothing left to love.
- 考虑一下 接受吧！ - 你动动头脑想一下
- Think about it. Take the offer. - You think about it.
他们为什么要卖Atom？因为他是与众不同的
Why does she want Atom? Because he's different from other bots!
是啊 是不一样 是小个 虚弱的
Yeah, he's different. He's smaller, weaker,
- 而且他会被揍的很惨的 - 他是拳击手
- and he's going to get his ass kicked. - He's a boxer.
我们叫他拳击 你教他拳击
We taught him to box. You taught him to box!
- 这个就是它的价值 - 我也是这么认为
- That's worth something. - I think it is, too.
我想这个值20万 20万大元
I think it's worth 200 grand. Two hundred grand.
我们可以整晚都在这里兜
We can go round and round this all night long.
看着我
Look at me.
但是绝对不会卖的
But it's not going to happen.
对不起我还有比赛
I got a fight to get to.
各位先生女士们 今晚...
Ladies and gentlemen, tonight,
即将带来的 钢铁擂台冠军杯
the march towards the Real Steel Championship
来到了底特律
makes its way through Detroit's
维吉尼亚州 史倍状中心
Virgin America Spectrum!
开始我们的第一轮排名赛
Kicking off the evening, in our first undercard,
二个头的暴君
the two-headed tyrant,
双子星
Twin Cities!
对手是第一次参加职业比赛的
Opposing Twin Cities, in his first professional fight,
让我们一起喊
hailing from parts unknown,
Atom
Atom!
- 跳得好 老板 - 谢谢
- Nice work, boss. - Thanks.
- 你切换到战斗模式了？- 当然
- Did you switch him to fight mode? - Of course.
- 双子星是训练来撕裂对手 - Atom 也可以
- This bot is tough to put down. - Atom can do it.
看看那里 那二个握着摇杆在荧幕后面的怪胎
Look over there. You see those geeks with the joysticks and consoles?
他们完全控制他们的机器人
They're controlling everything their bot does.
他们随时监看它的系统
They're monitoring his systems,
随时调整他的战术
seeing what he sees, stadium feeds of the fights.
这个不是以前我们对战的地下那种用遥控器的级别
This is not like the underground handheld remote bots
这是职业赛 你要了解到
we've been fighting. This is the League. Stand on that.
那我们要怎么做？
So what do we do?
我们要聪明一点 有耐心 然后祈祷
We fight smart, we be patient. And pray.
正经一点 不是那种祈祷
Seriously, pray.
准备好！
Ready!
- 准备好了 - 手举起来
- Ready! - Hands up.
拳手准备好了！ 开始！
Fighters ready! Fight!
交战开始
Engage.
滑动！ 右边！ 退后 右 左 左 掩护好
Slip! Right! Lean back. Right, left! Cover up!
低头 左勾拳
Duck! Left roundhouse!
该死的
Damn it.
闪左边！ 闪右边！防守好！
Lean left! Lean right! Cover up! Cover up!
- 发生什么事了？- 他要对上太多头了
- What's going on in there? - He's taking too many hits.
把手举起来
Get your hands up!
离开角落！ 移动！
Get out of that corner! Move!
他在被狠狠修理了 赶快告诉他怎么做！
He's getting killed in there! Tell him what to do!
对手有二个头 二个头都对着我们 而且没有盲点
That guy's got two heads, a foot of reach on us, and no blind spot.
对手一定有弱点 找出来吧！
He's got to have a weakness. Find it!
看到了 等一下 看到了！
Wait, wait, wait.
右手肩膀 右手肩膀 他有一个习惯动作
Right shoulder, right shoulder, right shoulder! He's got a tell!
每次出右拳的时候 他都有一个准备动作
He's got a hitch in his shoulder every time he throws that right bomb!
抓到了 看到没？又有准备动作了
We got him! See? Here it comes again!
低头！ 旋转！ 滑到左边！ 绕一圈！ 一 二！
Duck! Spin! Slide left! Roundhouse! One, two!
退后 退后一步 滑到左边！
Backstep. Backstep. Backstep. Lean right.
来吧 Charlie 跟上去！
Come on, Charlie! Get in there!
我们要缩近到对我们有利的距离
Got to get in close where he can't use that size and reach on us!
攻击左边身体 右边身体 再左边身体
Left to the body! Right to the body! Left to the body!
耶 有作用了！
Yeah, it's working!
继续低一点的姿势 左 右 左
Stay downstairs! Left, right, left!
- 这个模式没有用 - 左 右勾 滑动
- These program modes aren't working. - Left! Right hook, slip!
右上钩拳！ 左上钩全！躲左边 闪右边
Right uppercut! Left uppercut! Duck left. Counter right!
- 打到他 Atom！ - 看看Charlie的绝招
- Get him, Atom! - Here comes the Charlie Special.
三连击攻击身体！ 外面！ 里面！ 反向！
Three-punch combo to the body! Out! In! Counter!
- 一二一连击！ - 一二一连击！
- Two-one-two! - Two-one-two.
盯住他 ！ 前后分身 ！
Stay on him! Lunging right!
你要让他逃走右拳攻击身体！ 右直拳打头！
Don't let him go. Right to the body! Straight right to the head!
系统崩溃了！
We got a systems crash!
打倒他 Atom！
Get him, Atom!
怎么可能发生这种事？
This is not happening, man.
- 打倒他 Charlie！ - 左旋转
- Put him away, Charlie! - Spin left!
右旋转
Spin right!
干掉他
Finish him!
- 就是现在 - 右勾拳
- Do it! - Right uppercut!
倒了！
He's down!
1！2！3！
One! Two! Three!
4！5！6！
Four! Five! Six!
我们干掉他了 准备好！
We got him. Stay down!
结束比赛 击倒！
He's out! He's out!
耶！
Yeah!
回来！
Corner!
回到角落来！
Corner! Corner.
胜利！
Victory!
在一分47秒...
In a time of one minute, 47 seconds
第一回合......
of the first round,
Atom击败了...
Atom has defeat...
感谢各位今天晚上的观看
I want to thank everyone for coming out tonight!
我们从垃圾场来的的小巨人 击倒了职业级的机器人
Our little bot from the junkyard got a shot at a League fight.
爽不爽？
How about that?
最后我要对一个背地里操作的女孩说...
And the last thing I want to say to a special girl who won't be named,
法罗 兰蔻娃
Farra Lemkova.
她想买我的机器人 用你们的钱来操作比赛
That instead of buying my robot, using your money to control this sport...
- 就是她 - 不是我说的
- That's it! - I'm not done.
你为什么不给小巨人一个最大的机会？
Why not give the littlest guy the biggest shot?
因为我敢打赌 你不敢给我们这个机会
Because I bet if you give him a shot, he'll surprise you!
大家想不想看小巨人
Wouldn't you like to see a little guy
对抗联盟冠军
get a shot at the Real Steel Championship?
我要挑战宙斯！
I challenge Zeus to a fight.
任何时间 任何地点！
Any time, any place, anywhere!
告诉我们 ！ 我们就来！
You name it! We will be there!
我来为各位安排这场比赛
I'm going to get us that fight!
Atom Atom Atom...
Atom, Atom, Atom...
那是很没脑的举动 你就这样挑战宙斯？
That was a ballsy move, you challenging Zeus like that.
那只是一时的冲动
That's one thing to call it.
很多人会很想看的
A lot of people would like to see that.
- 是的 大家都想 - 听这个小鬼说的 天啊！
- You're damn right they would. - You listening to this kid? Jeez!
- 好比赛 兄弟 - 谢谢你
- Good fight, fellas. - Thanks, man.
- 看看这个 庆祝一下 - 耶
- Look at this. Let's celebrate. - Yeah.
- 好吧 7-3分账 对不对？- 耶 我7你3
- All right, 70-30, right? - Yeah, 70 for me and 30 for you.
- 对对对 - 很好笑！
- That's so right. - That's very funny.
- 我就说我们不应该卖掉它 - 喔 喔 喔！
- I told you we shouldn't have sold him. - OK. No, no, no.
我想起来了 谁才对？说啊 说出来“Max是对的”？
I remember now. Who's right? Say who's right. Say "Max is right."
好啦好啦 你才是对的！
All right, all right. All right.
- 我们合作无间是吧 - 不是不是 要说“Max是对的”
- We're a good team. - No, no. Max is right.
不敢相信 这么多钱 感谢你 双子星！
That was unbelievable. Thank you, Twin Cities.
- 收好了？- 耶
- We set? - Yeah.
- 我们去庆祝了！ - Charlie男孩
- Let's do it. - Charlie boy.
- 里奇 我才正想要打给你 - 噢？是吗？
- Ricky, I was just going to call you. - Oh, yeah.
我是真的打算打给你
I actually really was going to call you.
没事 不用在意
Don't worry about that.
真的是了不起的比赛！
That was a heck of a fight.
恭喜二位 真的是太好了！
Congratulations to both of you. That was good.
真的是了不起的战斗 干得好 小朋友
It was an amazing fight. That was a great job, young man.
- 来吧！兄弟 - 干嘛？
- Come on, man. - What?
- 你不会是说真的吧？- 你以为我在开玩笑？
- You serious? - You thought I was joking
我说“见你一次就海扁你一次”
when I said I'd beat you within an inch of your life?
你以为我是开玩笑？告诉你 绝对不是！
He thought that was a joke. It wasn't a joke.
我小孩在这里 我也准备钱要给你了 不要这样
I got a kid here. And I have your money. We don't have a problem.
我看你也不敢
I'm sure you do,
但是不只是因为钱是吧？你都知道的
but I think we know it's about much more than money, don't we?
好的 你要多少？二万 二万五 三万够不够？
All right. What do you want? You want 25, 30? You want 30 grand?
- 我手头上有现金 - 是哦！对啊
- I got the money in cash here. - Yeah, right.
赶快跑！Max 跑 快跑！
Let's go! Max, go! Go, go! Run!
- 赶快跑 跟上 快！ - 赶快抓住他！
- Run! Come on. Keep up, keep up! - Get him now!
跑 快！
Run! Come on!
放开他！放开他！
Get off him! Get off him!
过来！
Come here!
嗨 里奇！
Hey, Ricky.
那是他的钱 跟他无关
That's his money! Leave him out of this!
停
Stop!
停！
把所有的钱都拿走 全拿走！
Take all his money. Take it all.
小朋友 你的朋友是个人渣
Your friend's a real dirt bag, kid.
他是我父亲
He's my father!
看来可以少扁你一次了
Well. Looks like a little less than an inch of your life.
嗯 好好的给你上一课
Well, buddy, that will teach him.
就像以前一样 Charlie男孩
Just like old times, Charlie boy!
走吧 兄弟们
Let's go, boys.
对不起 Max 我很抱歉
I'm sorry, Max. I'm sorry. Sorry.
- 我们来这里做什么？- Max 只是...
- What are we doing here? - Max, just...
来找法罗？她是不是打给你了？我们要跟宙斯比赛了？
Is it Farra? She called you, didn't she? We're going to get the Zeus fight.
不是宙斯 我想了很多 然后......
It's not the Zeus people. I've been thinking about all this, and...
Max
Max!
很高兴见到你
It's so good to see you.
- 为什么她在这里？- 你最好还是现在跟她回去
- What is she doing here? - It's better if you go with her now.
我们被痛扁了 所以你打电话给她来接我？
We get beat up, so you call her to come and get me?
他被打了 我就说他没法照顾好Max的！
He's been beat up. I told you he couldn't take care of him!
是的 我打给他们 你看我们 真是一团糟
Yeah. I called her. Look at us. We're a mess.
我们很好 叫他们走
We're fine. She can leave!
Atom打得很好 我们可以把钱再赚回来
Atom's fighting good. We can make the money back.
Charlie 拜托！
Charlie, please.
只是...
Just...
Charlie 我们过得很好
Charlie, we're doing so good.
Charlie 拜托 不要
Charlie, please, no.
不要 不要 不要
Don't. Don't. Don't.
拜托 拜托
Please. Please.
相信我 这样对你比较好 好吗？
Trust me, kid. It's better this way, all right?
你以为这样对我比较好 其实不是的
I know you think you know what's right, but you don't.
你还年轻 你不懂
You're too young. You don't know.
看着我 相信我！
Look at me, trust me.
而且法律上 她有你的监护权 我还能怎么做？
And legally she has custody, so what can I do?
我还能做什么？
What can I do?
我不要你的钱 马文
I don't want your money, Marvin.
Max 我们有自己的游泳池哦
Max, we have our own swimming pool
而且我们有按摩浴缸 还有很多好玩的玩具给你玩
and we have a hot tub and a lot of super fun toys to play with.
你要玩玩嘛？很好玩的哦
Do you want to play with them? It's going to be fun.
情况如何？
What's going on?
谢谢你 他根本不跟我讲话
He won't even talk to me, so thanks for that, Charlie.
我先到车子里面等
I'm going to wait in the car.
你不想讲话？好 我说
You don't want to talk, fine. I'll talk.
你要我说什么？我很抱歉？
What do you want me to say? I'm sorry?
从一开始就是这样
You knew from day one what this was.
从你开始决定上车就是这样
You decided to take the ride.
你以为我可以跟你那个破烂堆捡到...
You thought me, you, and a little robot from the junk heap
的破机器人一起坐着看夕阳？
were going to ride off into the sunset?
你看错我了
No, you forgot who I was!
你应该过的好一点的生活...
You deserve better...
...比我还好
than me.
拜托说几句话吧？
Will you say something, please?
我努力过了 你还要我怎么做？
I tried. What do you want from me?
我要你为我奋斗
I want you to fight for me.
这就是我想要的
That's all I ever wanted.
翻译：闲闲的猛男 校对：目前没有
不要问
Don't ask.
Max走了？
So no Max.
最好的安排 马文及黛博拉他们有钱 会好好照顾Max
It's better this way. Marv and Debra have money. Max is set.
你有没有看到他看你的样子？
Did you not see the way he looked at you?
就像我看我爹的样子
That's the way I looked at my dad.
我多想再重温那种感觉
Even now I would give anything to have that back.
你父亲不一样 他从一开始就跟你在一起
Your dad was special. He was in your corner from day one.
我 我早就搞砸了
Me, come on. I blew it.
我搞砸了
I blew it.
当Max出生的时候...
When Max was born I just...
...我吓傻了
freaked out.
你没有感到满足吗？
But something would have been better than nothing.
不对 是手足无措
I wouldn't know where to start.
- 我不满足 - 不 你很幸福
- Yeah, you do. - I don't.
- 你是的 - 不是
- You do. - No.
你是的
You do.
我要走了
I got to go.
开了1200英里就为了这个吻？
Twelve hundred miles for a kiss.
值得 值得！
Worth it. Worth it.
去找他 Charlie！
Go get him, Charlie.
你说得好像你爹的口气
You sound like your dad.
我知道你认为我遗弃了你
Look, I know you think I abandoned you,
而且我还真的这样做了
and I guess I did originally.
你还卖掉我
Then you sold me.
Charlie？
Charlie.
这个地方一点都不欢迎你
You have no business being here.
没错 你有全部的监护权 他是你的
That's true. You've got full custody. He's yours.
而且我知道所有的事都是我的错 但是请你让我...
And I know I've done all kinds of wrong by this kid, but if you'll let me...
...我想要做一些补偿
I'd just like to do one thing right.
好的
Right.
- 讲到哪里了？- 你卖掉我
- Where were we? - You sold me.
哦 对了 耶 没错
Right, yeah, that happened.
- 等一下 什么？- 然后我们被痛扁一顿
- Wait, what? - Then we had our asses kicked.
然后你还要睡在一个破卡车里面
And you slept on a shelf in a truck, and it was awful.
- 很危险 - 非常危险
- And dangerous. - Really dangerous.
我知道 天啊 我真的很对不起你
I mean, I know. God. I'm sorry.
你来就是要说这个？就是要说你很抱歉？
That's why you came? To say you're sorry?
不 不止这些
No. I mean, yes. Yes.
我来还要再说 我了解了
But no. No, I came to tell you that I heard you.
我懂了 虽然我有一点迟钝 但是我懂了
I got it. I'm a little slow, but I got it.
我知道我去流浪了 当你出生的时候
I know you had a bum ride, and I wasn't there and I should have been.
我实在不应该去的
I should have been.
你妈妈真的是...
Your mom was...
她很好是吧 很酷吧？
She was cool, wasn't she?
是的
She was.
她是最好的
She was the coolest.
耶 是的
Yeah, she was.
对她的事 我也很遗憾
And I'm sorry about... what happened with her.
马克思 我没法让时间倒流
And I can't get those years back, Max,
但是现在我来了...
but I'm here right now...
...就像你看到的 我已经准备好要为你战斗
and if you're up for it, I'm ready to fight.
跟宙斯的比赛安排好了
We got the Zeus fight.
真的？
What?
没错 安排好了
No, no, we didn't.
准备跟宙斯战斗
You got the Zeus fight.
黛博拉 可以请你通融吗？
So what do you say, Debra?
可不可以让我们在一起奋战 最后一次？
Can we do this one last thing?
- 就一晚 - 我们就这个小小要求
- One night. - It's all we need. Thank you.
我们很可能被痛宰 但是至少我们在一起奋斗
We'll probably get our asses kicked, but at least we'll go down swinging.
耶？你怎么决定？
Yeah? What do you say?
欢迎来到纽约的滨中心及观看钢铁擂台冠军大赛
Welcome to New York's Bing Arena and the Real Steel Championship Bout.
提姆 这是场我们不敢想象会安排的比赛
Tim, it's the fight we never thought we'd see.
宙斯 永远不败的WRB拳王
Zeus, the undefeated WRB champion,
迎战最近新崛起的初级的Atom
against the underdog, rising star Atom.
拳王的老板答应了这场比赛
The champ's handlers have agreed to fight
打破了联盟循环赛的规则
outside the circle of well-known League bots,
而且准备给观众一场真正的重量级的对抗
and have decided to give the people a true David versus Goliath spectacle.
提姆 告诉我 拳王是不是脑袋进水了？
Now, Tim, help me out on this. Has the Zeus camp lost their mind?
有史以来最伟大的机器人格斗拳王
The greatest robot boxer of all time
为了跟一个第二代的 Atom 战斗而交出他的腰带？
gives a shot at the belt to a G-2 named Atom?
赫伯 如果你问松本先生 宙斯团队是不是疯了
Well, Herb, if you ask Tak Mashido, Team Zeus has lost their minds.
他可能会用一贯冷酷的表情回你
Now, he may look cool as he enters the arena,
然后用轻蔑的表情看待这场比赛
but he has made no bones about his disdain for this match up.
前几天我们的摄影机试着要补抓这号表情
Our cameras tried to catch up with him earlier this week.
看看这个片段 松本先生甚至根本不想停下来跟媒体讲话
Look at this clip. Mashido wouldn't even stop to talk to the press,
好像这场比赛是是侮辱了他伟大的创造物
referring only to this fight as an insult to his creation.
Charlie Atom的教练做的已经不只是跳级挑战宙斯
Now, Max Kenton, Atom's trainer, did more than just challenge Zeus.
还是公开的挑战
He did so publicly.
这个挑战对拳王的公关形象是一个大挑战
The challenge went viral and created a PR nightmare for the champ.
没有任何合约 但是我相信拳王的团队很清楚他们在做什么
No argument there. And I think the Zeus camp knows exactly what they're doing.
那就是他们做的 来吧
That they do. Come on.
给一个无名小卒一个机会来挑战
Giving a shot at the belt to a nobody from nowhere.
那个垃圾厂的挑战者？这一切都只是噱头罢了
This "junkyard dog," if you will. That's a marketing stunt.
而且从观众的反应看起来 很奏效！
And judging from this crowd, that stunt is working.
我们赢不了 是吧？
We can't win, can we?
很难说
We'll see.
挑战者正慢慢的走到他的角落
As the challenger makes his way into the arena,
你可以感受到激情的汹涌
you can hear the surge of excitement.
Atom已经抵达WRB的比赛现场
Atom has arrived onto the WRB scene with a vengeance,
用他“像人类”的外观
using a style, some would call it human-like,
他战斗的模式是非常少见的
that bot fighting has rarely seen.
Atom 跟他的迷你训练员已经踏上比赛场地
Atom and his pint-size trainer step into the ring
看看法罗的表情 说明了一切
and the look on Farra Lemkova's face says it all.
欢迎来到大联盟 年轻人
Welcome to the bigs, junior!
现在的赌盘开出来是1赔5 赌Atom撑不过第一回合
I'm giving one-to-five odds that Atom don't make it out the first round.
有人要赌吗？
Who wants some?
现在可以开始下注了
I'll take some of that action.
嗨 我要下注
Hey, there! I'll take some of that action.
最近如何... 伙伴？
How's it going... partner?
谁是你的伙伴？
Partner?
很好 我下十万 怎么样？刺不刺激？
That's great. How about a hundred K? Is that funny?
十万？赌Atom 撑不过第一回合？
Hundred K says Atom doesn't see round two.
你有带那么多现金？
You carrying around that kind of scratch?
- 耶 - 十万？
- Yeah. - Hundred K?
记得 我在101区 C 排
Tell you what. Remember section 101, row C,
然后把我的钱拿过来
and you can bring me my money right to my seat.
101 C排 ？十万 ？
101, row C? Hundred K?
你听到的 “宅男”！
You heard me, homey.
-宅男 ？- 是的 ？
- Homey? - Right?
宅在家里的大男孩
Homeboy!
没事 保镖们 酷！
All right. Peace out, posse.
来吧甜心 我们走吧
Come on, sugar. Let's go.
- 永远不败的 - 表演时间
- Never beaten. - It's showtime!
永不恐惧的
Never threatened.
拳击场上的王者
The king of the ring,
机器人的统治者
the ruler of robots!
欢迎我们王者宙斯！
Bow down to the mighty Zeus!
哦！shit ！
Oh, shit!
好牛
That was awesome.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
各位先生女士们
Ladies and gentlemen,
在五回合的拳击规则下
in a bout scheduled for five rounds
进行世界拳击冠军大赛
for the World Robot Boxing Championship,
在我右手边的是 挑战者Atom
in the corner to my right, the challenger, Atom!
表现一下
Showboat!
以及 在我左边的是...
And in the corner to my left,
整个宇宙最伟大的......
the undeniable champion of this universe
以及所有宇宙最厉害的...
and any other universe known or unknown,
宙斯王者
the mighty Zeus!
现在 各位先生女士们准备好
And now, ladies and gentlemen, are you ready
钢铁擂台
for Real Steel!
就是我们期待已久的！
This is what it's all about!
铃声响起 马上开始比赛了
There's the starting bell and we are underway.
机器人慢慢的离开他们的角落
The bots emerge from their corners.
宙斯一下就把Atom打趴 Atom已经倒下了
Zeus decks Atom, and he is already down.
站起来！
On your feet!
看来又是一出宙斯式的惨剧
Looks like we are in for another Zeus clinic.
裁判马特盖格已经出来开始倒数了
Referee Matt Geiger coming in the ring to start the count.
站起来！
Get up!
用手撑起来！站起来！
Push up! Stand up!
但是看看 小巨人已经站起来了
But look at this. The little bot's back on his feet
准备迎接宙斯的第二轮猛攻
to get a second blistering attack from Zeus!
不到十秒时间 Atom又一次倒下了
Atom is down for the second time in less than ten seconds.
- 太强了 - 好样的 那才像我的人！
- He's too strong! - That's my boy right there!
站起来继续比赛
Get up and get in the game!
来吧！ 不 拜托 Atom 站起来！
Come on! No, please Atom, get up! Please!
站起来！ 站起来！ 站起来！
Get up! Get up! Get up!
又一次 挑战者站了起来！
Once again, the challenger finds his feet!
低头 后退！
Lean back!
Atom被连续击逼到了绳索边上
Atom's getting pummeled into the corner!
- 离开角落！ - 移动！
- Get out of there! - Move!
一阵摧毁式的近身攻击
A demolishing inside shot.
把手举起来！
Get your hands up!
举起来！
Hands up!
揍扁那个罐头
Crush that little can!
离开角落
Get out of the corner!
肯顿绝望的命令他的机器人离开死亡的角落
Kenton desperately trying to command his robot out of that suicide corner.
蹲低一点！
Get your feet under you!
晚安 表演机器人！
Good night, sparring bot!
今晚只是时间长了一点 但是宙斯又一次要击倒了...
It might have taken Zeus a bit longer, but he's done it again!
Atom第三次倒下了 也可能是今晚最后一次倒下
Atom is down for the third and possibly final time tonight.
- 站起来！ - 2！
- Stand up! - Two!
3！
Three!
Atom 站起来！
Atom, get up!
- 起来 Atom - 起来 Atom
- Get up, Atom. - Get up, Atom.
- 6 ！7！ - 起来！
- Six! Seven! - Get up!
8！ 9！
Eight! Nine!
真不敢相信！似曾相识 小巨人又一次站了起来
I don't believe this! Against all odds, this little bot is on his feet again.
来吧 Atom！
Come on, Atom!
它撑不下去的
He can't survive this!
- 来吧 Charlie！ - 右上勾拳
- Come on, Charlie! - Right uppercut!
Atom 使出一记绝招！
Atom has landed a punch!
宙斯被出乎意料的上钩拳击中 摇晃的退后
Zeus is stunned as he reels back from an uppercut that he never saw coming!
前进！
Advance!
退一步 出右拳！
Fade back, counter right!
右交叉拳！ 右交叉拳！ 右交叉拳！ 左勾拳！
Right cross! Right cross! Right cross! Left hook!
- 来吧！ 上吧！ - 击倒他！
- Let's go! Come on! - Take him down!
第一次 Atom占了优势
For the first time in his dominant run,
宙斯第一次遇到一个打不退的对手
Zeus has met a bot who simply won't back down!
群众已经疯狂了 宙斯使出浑身解数
The crowd is going nuts! Zeus gives it everything he's got
第一回合已经剩下15秒钟了
as we reach the last 15 seconds of round one!
宙斯把Atom逼到角落 使出双组合拳
Zeus corners Atom, going double duty with both fists!
上击 下击！好像钟摆上上下下
Downtown, uptown, as the clock winds down!
- 手举起来 下巴压低 - 蹲低一点 蹲低一点
- Hands up, chin down. - Stay low, stay low!
只剩5秒钟 拳王使出了活塞式的组合拳
Only five seconds left, as here comes that piston-packed right of the champ!
铃声响起了 不敢相信 Atom竟然撑过了第一回合
There's the bell! I don't believe it. Somehow Atom has survived.
竟然进到了第二回合 观众都起鸡皮疙瘩了
We will have a second round. And the crowd here is thrilled!
他办到了！ 耶！ 回来角落！
He made it! Yeah! Corner!
我们要赶快离开这里 马上！
We got to get out of here. We got to get out of here now!
走另外一边 快点！
We got to go this way. Come on!
好吧 你坐下吧！
OK, you sit down.
- 走吧 宅男 - 好啦
- Let's go, homey. - All right.
我一会就回来 宝贝
I'll be back for you, baby.
把你的手拿开 我自己走
Get your hands off me!
二个角落都在忙的检查他们的机器人
Both corners furiously working on their bots.
观众们本来都预期今晚是个大屠杀
This crowd came here tonight expecting a massacre,
但是迎来的是一场势均力敌的战斗
but instead they're getting a war!
- 你弄好了吗？- 耶
- You got it? - Yeah.
好样的 来吧！继续！
All right. Here we go.
怎么搞的？
What is happening?
他已经完全准备好应付任何突发状况 没有事的
He is fully prepared for all possible contingencies. He will be fine.
然后呢？
What next?
第二回合
Round two.
Atom 第二回合 Atom 不可思议的挑战者
Round two kicks off, and incredibly the challenger, Atom,
勇敢的挑战拳王
is giving the champ a run for his money.
宙斯揣着小巨人 把它像个罐子丢到绳边
Zeus tosses the smaller bot across the ring like a tin can!
肯顿让他的机器人打出一个三连击 打在拳王的脸上！
Kenton working his bot with a trifecta of straight rights to the champ's dome!
他们并列在战场 震耳欲聋的欢呼声
Toe-to-toe they stand, trading deafening blows!
不管绳圈旁的教练想什么伎俩都没有用了
Whatever strategy either corner had cooked up has been destroyed!
金属对战金属 钢铁大战钢铁
Metal bashing metal. Steel smashing steel.
这是一场大战
This is a brawl!
观众已经都站起来了 拉长脖子看二个机器人残杀对方
The crowd is on their feet, watching two machines driven to kill each other!
也即将要发生什么大事了
Something has to give, and it does!
Atom 又一次倒下了
Atom goes down again!
今晚再一次次的点亮恶斗的战场
Lights out for the junkyard dog who put on a heck of a show here tonight!
又一次 Atom又站起来了
And yet again, Atom rises up.
肯顿逼不得已要跳线接上 才可以使机器人回到比赛
Kenton must have hardwired this bot with the will to go on!
第四回合中段 拳王想马上击倒对手 结束比赛
Midway through round four, and Zeus is looking to end this thing right now.
拳王已经豁出一切 好像不打算回到更衣室了
The champ is holding nothing back as he cracks open the hurt locker!
Atom在绳索边摇摇晃晃 他已经昏了！
Atom is stumbling around the ring, apparently disoriented and dazed!
- 手举起来！ - 出了什么事？
- Hands up! - What's going on?
我猜语音控制已经坏掉了 没有反应！
I think the voice recog is shot! He's not responding!
宙斯就像完美的暴力武器 钻进Atom的腹部
Zeus has found yet another gear of violence, drilling Atom's midsection.
不！住手！帮一下手啊！
No! Stop! Do something!
他已经听不到了！
He can't hear me!
但是铃声又响起了 小机器人的表现已经震惊了整个世界
But the bell sounds, and once again this little robot has stunned the world!
我们完蛋了 Max 他听不到我的语音指挥了 这是谋杀 我们认输吧！
We're done, Max! He can't hear me. This is murder. We've had enough.
- 我把语音辨识关掉了 - 又怎样？他听不到我的声音了
- I'm disabling the voice recognition. - He can't hear me!
- 是的 但是他看得到你！ - 你说什么？
- Yes, but he can see you! - What?
我切换到映射模式 你要教他怎么做
I'm putting him in shadow mode. Show him what to do.
不用语音辨识模式 它可以移动的更快
Without the voice recognition, he'll move even faster!
不行 不行！
No way. No way!
看看他们 他们已经被打晕了！
Look at them. They are freaking out!
那个有钱女孩已经抓着他指指点点了！
Rich girl is ripping him a new one over there!
你知道为什么吗？因为他们已经害怕了
Do you know why? Because they're scared.
因为Atom可以做到其他机器人做不到的
Because Atom can do things no other bot has ever done.
- 但是我做不到 - 行的 你可以的
- But I can't do it! - Yes, you can.
- 我不行啦 - 不 你行的
- I can't. - Yes, you can.
让他知道怎么做 你必须自己战斗最后一个回合
Show him what to do. You have to fight the last round.
不要拜托我 不要
Don't ask me. Don't.
Charlie... 拜托 我求你
Charlie... please. I beg you.
你要用那个小狗眼神“杀”死我？
Are you kidding me with those eyes?
该死的！
Damn it!
耶！
Yes!
真不敢相信我会这么做
I can't believe I'm doing this.
我知道你能了解 不管你是不是听得到
I know you're in there! I'm not sure if you're getting this or what,
但是我确定你了解
but I know you're in there!
- 肯顿 打还是不打？- 打 给我一分钟
- Kenton. In or out? - In. Give me a minute.
我知道你听不见我说的 但是你可以看得到我 所以看着我
I know you can't hear me, but you can see me, so watch me!
仔细看着...我
Watch... me.
- 你知道你是对一个机器人讲话 - 我知道 闭嘴！
- You know you're talking to a robot. - I know. Shut up.
注意看着我
Watch me.
这场如史诗般的大战已经
An epic battle being waged here tonight,
马上要进入第五回合 最后的一个回合
as the fifth and final round gets underway.
来吧 Atom！
Come on, Atom!
等一下 你有没有看到？
Wait a second. Are you seeing this?
Charlie肯顿正在场外映射指导回击
Charlie Kenton is shadowboxing just outside the ring!
看来Atom有动作映射功能
It looks like Atom has a shadow function.
所以基本上 Charlie肯顿就像是
So, basically, that means Charlie Kenton
在最后一个回合自己上场对抗宙斯
is fighting the last round of this fight against Zeus.
但是看起来一点帮助都没有 Atom又被逼到了角落
It doesn't seem to help, because Atom is backed up against the ropes again.
帮帮他！ 还击！
Help him! Fight back!
还不到时候
Not yet.
松本亲自监督宙斯的操作人员
Tak Mashido supervising personally as Zeus hammers down,
愤怒的想马上击倒Atom 结束比赛
furiously trying to end this thing once and for all.
告诉各位大家 拳王看起来累了
I got to tell you, folks, the champ looks tired.
拳王看起来已经没力了
This robot seems to be running on empty.
不敢相信！Atom在挑衅宙斯
I don't believe it. Atom is taunting Zeus.
- 切换到涡轮加速！ - 他认为还不够！
- Switch to turbo! - He's actually asking for more.
拜托救救他！
Please do something!
- 还不到时候 - 对了 Charlie 还没到时候
- Not yet. - That's right, Charlie. Not yet.
现在使出活塞拳！
Nitrous pistons, now!
他已经没有办法再支持住了
He's not going to last much longer!
- 回击！ - 还不到时候
- Fight back! - Not yet.
坚持住！
Hang in there!
Atom对宙斯的机关枪拳一点都没有办法招架
Atom is riddled with the nitrous-fueled Gatling guns of Zeus's blows!
Atom！ Atom！ Atom！ Atom！
Atom! Atom! Atom! Atom!
等他没力 等他力竭！ 还没！
Wait him out, wait him out! Not yet!
宙斯慢下来了！
Zeus is slowing down!
拳王的动力已经接近报废了
The champ's power core is clearly depleted.
Charlie 拜托！
Charlie, please!
嗨 小鬼！
Hey, kid.
- 时候到了 - 现在！
- Now. - Now!
靠近他！
Get in there!
揍扁这个婊子 打的他开花！
Knock that little bitch! Bust him open!
耶！ 这就对了！
Yeah! That's right!
想想办法！！
Do something!
走开！
Move!
最高级别 切换到手动控制！
Override. Switching to manual.
松本吃惊的举动 他竟然亲手手动操作他的机器人
In a shocking move, Tak Mashido is manually operating his robot personally!
- 攻击身体！ 靠近他！ - 打倒他 Atom！
- Work the body! Get inside him! - Get him, Atom!
大家看啊！拳王现在只能拼命的想办法站着
Look at this! The champ is trying desperately to stay on his feet,
但是肯顿一点都不留情 一拳一拳的轰炸宙斯的身体！
but Kenton is relentless, landing blow after blow after blow to the body!
左！右！左！右！
Left! Right! Left! Right!
Atom打出一记重要的上勾拳！ 宙斯倒下了！
A huge uppercut by Atom! Zeus is down!
这个小机器人今天晚上的顽强表现
This little bot has dug deep here tonight
深深的触动每一个人的心
and shown something damn near heart!
1 2 3......
One, two, three,
4 5 6 7......
four, five, six, seven...
宙斯站起来了！
He's good!
宙斯已经快站不住了 但是肯顿及...
Zeus gets to his feet, but Kenton has Atom on him again,
...Atom没有放过他 拳如雨下！
landing punch after punch!
松本跟他的超级机器人一点都没有办法回应
Tak Mashido and his super bot have no answer.
宙斯夹住了Atom的左臂 但是肯顿一点都不惧怕
Zeus pins Atom's left arm, but Kenton is undaunted!
局面竟然到了这个地步 各位！
It all comes down to this, folks!
甩开他 Charlie！ 就是现在！
Drop him, Charlie! Now!
- 肯顿已经快把冠军... - 不 铃声响起来了
- Kenton is about to drop the champ... - No! There's the bell!
铃声救了宙斯！！
Zeus is saved by the bell!
不可思议 比赛进入到裁判判决
Amazingly, we will go to the judges' cards!
去吧！
各位先生女士们 经过了五个艰苦的回合以后
Ladies and gentlemen, after five rounds,
裁判的判决已经出来了
we go to the judges' scorecards.
第一位裁判的判决 47-48
Judge Number One scores the fight 47-48.
第二位裁判的判决 48-46
Judge Number Two scores the fight 48-46.
第三为裁判的判决 47-46
And Judge Number Three scores the fight 47-46,
世界冠军成功的保住了他的冠军头衔
for the winner and still World Robot Boxing champion,
宙斯！
Zeus!
法拉 兰蔻娃
Farra Lemkova,
的机器人今天晚上的表现比你们说的差多了
you got way more than you bargained for tonight.
有人说你的机器人赢了判决 但是输了比赛
Some would say that your bot won the decision but lost the fight.
她看起来很不爽
She looks pissed.
比赛过程比我们想象的还要久一点
It took a little longer than we thought,
但是结果还是如预期的一样
but the result is as expected.
我们赢了 宙斯还是永远不败的
We won. Zeus is still undefeated.
松本先生 我想问的是...
对于你们今晚这场那么羞辱的比赛 被惨痛的修理...
Any comment on the absolutely humiliating near loss
...还差点输了 你有没有话要说？
your bot suffered tonight?
- 没说 - 不予置评
- Nothing. - No comment.
Max Max在哪里？
Max. Where's Max?
他在那里...Max！
There he is. Max.
大家都称你的机器人是“平民冠军"
They're already calling your bot "the people's champion."
你怎么说呢？
What do you say to that?
平民冠军？
People's champion?
对我来说 很好！
Sounds pretty good to me.
爹？爹！
Dad? Dad!
爹！
Dad!
我真的想让你知道
I really want you to know...
不 你需要知道...
No, I need you to know.
不用担心
Don't worry.
我会保密的
Your secret's safe with me.
等一下！
Wait here. Wait here.
耶！
Yes!
翻译：闲闲的猛男 校对：目前没有